<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/]]></id><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-13T22:04:28.066Z]]></updated><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-13T22:04:28.066Z]]></updated><category term="FEATURE"/><title><![CDATA[Behind the Mac creator celebrates his literary icon]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/02/behind-the-mac-creator-celebrates-his-literary-icon/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Behind the Mac creator celebrates his literary icon<br/>Barry Jenkins on James Baldwin, Filming Black Skin and Filmmaking in the iPhone Era<br/>Oscar-winning director Barry Jenkins says he “stumbled into filmmaking,” attending Florida State University for some years before discovering its film school. “I went to film school right at the turn between old school cinema and new school cinema,” Jenkins says, “so we actually learned to edit films on these things called flat beds … you have to actually physically cut the film and tape it back together. So, doing that for a full year and then transitioning to what they call non-linear editing, it was shocking.
<br/>“But I took the lessons with me,” he continues. “Only make the cuts you absolutely have to make.”
<br/>In last year’s Behind the Mac campaign that celebrates creators using Mac in their work, Jenkins is seen holding his MacBook Pro while standing under an umbrella in the rain. The director was exporting the final cut of his 2017 Academy Award-winning feature film, “Moonlight.”
<br/>Trained in traditional and modern filmmaking, Jenkins blends his craft with digital equipment like his ARRI Alexa camera, MacBook Pro and even his new iPad Pro. “These Arri cameras and the Apple platform are the two things that have helped me become the maker that I am,” Jenkins says.
<br/>His latest film, adapted from James Baldwin’s “If Beale Street Could Talk,” is a cautionary tale about black life in America in the 1970s, spotlighting the hardships a young couple face navigating a changing world around them. The novel was published in 1974, six years after Martin Luther King Jr.’s assassination in 1968, and a decade after the passage of the 1964 Civil Rights Act.
<br/>Baldwin’s literary tone is critical and unapologetic about his analysis of the state of the world around him. He crafts a delicate balance between the beauty and the brutality of America.
<br/>In Jenkins’s adaptation, that balance is achieved through portraits of moments shared between Tish (played by KiKi Layne) and Fonny (Stephan James), from the streets of Harlem to the West Village, to the bulletproof glass at the Manhattan Detention Complex — or the Tombs.
<br/>“My job in making this film, from the craft standpoint, from the aesthetic standpoint, was about trying to translate interiority into sounds and images, and to do so with the words of James Baldwin.”
<br/>To translate Baldwin’s words into moving pictures, Tish narrates the events that led to her and Fonny’s current status: in love, expecting and fighting for Fonny’s freedom after his wrongful arrest.
<br/>“The movie is composed of memory streams and nightmares and so how does 19-year-old Tish, how does <em>she</em> view Harlem?” Jenkins continues. “How does <em>she</em> want to remember it? And once we hit on that, that’s when the whole world opened up for us.”
<br/>“If Beale Street Could Talk” is the first English-language fiction adaptation of Baldwin, a feat with its own set of unique challenges.
<br/>“Literature is a very interior medium, it’s all about the interior voice,” Jenkins says. “And cinema, it’s about externally acting out in a certain way. You know, sounds and images. You’re not necessarily allowed to be inside the character, and James Baldwin, the power of his writing is all about the interior voice. So my job in making this film, from the craft standpoint, from the aesthetic standpoint, was about trying to translate interiority into sounds and images, and to do so with the words of James Baldwin.”
<br/>Shot on an ARRI Alexa 65, “Beale Street” gives audiences a close, intimate look at black life. Jenkins is grateful for the ability to capture the intimacies of black family and love, dreamed up by his literary icon, in such a large format.
<br/>“The history of [cinema] is all tied to 35 mm emulsion,” Jenkins explains. “These cameras now are programmable computer chips so you can write the algorithms to dictate how they behave, how they perceive light. In the past, you were limited in some ways by how certain film stocks were created and what their dynamic range was. Now, whenever we set up to make a film, we can program the computer … from scratch. So right away, we’re building these cameras to prioritise darker colours, by which I mean darker skin tones. It’s very freeing.”
<br/>Beyond the new cameras, filmmaking still requires a bit of magic. Enter the editor.
<br/>Joi McMillon is a longtime Jenkins collaborator. One of the two Oscar-nominated editors on “Moonlight,” she “breathes” Avid on the Mac Pro. McMillon worked with Jenkins and cinematographer James Laxton to bring the film to life.
<br/>In one scene, Fonny and Daniel (Brian Tyree Henry) spend hours in Fonny’s apartment catching up, moving from small talk to something troubling for Daniel.
<br/>“It’s kind of like a scene within a scene, and they change up the lighting and the angle and so as an audience member, you’re not exhausted by being somewhere for that long,” McMillon explains. “There’s now new information in each section of that part of the film.”
<br/>Jenkins wanted the audience to feel the energy being transferred between Fonny and Daniel. A camera slides slowly between them, a progression deeper and deeper into Daniel’s mind and Fonny’s reaction.
<br/>“There’s such warmth on Fonny and Daniel’s skin and yet what they’re talking about is so dark and scary and I just love the juxtaposition of that,” McMillon says. “The way it’s shot makes you feel like you’re sitting at the table with them.”
<br/>That immersion is now a Jenkins staple. Audiences sat at a similar table in a diner in “Moonlight,” and even floated in the ocean with those characters.
<br/>Today Jenkins, McMillon and the “Beale Street” family are once again on the awards circuit. The film is nominated for three Oscars: Best Supporting Actress (Regina King), Best Original Music Score (Nicholas Britell) and Best Adapted Screenplay (Jenkins).
<br/>“Even the old school cats that are embracing these new tools … they get down and dirty digitally.”
<br/>Up next: An Amazon series based on Coulson Whitehead’s “The Underground Railroad.” Jenkins jokes this will round out his artistic bucket list: “Make a movie about where I was from, and that became ‘Moonlight.’ I also wanted to adapt my favourite author, and that’s ‘Beale Street.’ And the last was I wanted to make something about the condition of American slavery. And that’s ‘The Underground Railroad.’” 
<br/>As Jenkins ticks off his list, he acknowledges a new class of filmmakers he says he’s sure will lap him soon. “Even the old school cats that are embracing these new tools … they get down and dirty digitally,” Jenkins says. “Steven Soderbergh has been working almost exclusively off the iPhone for the last few years.” (Soderbergh’s latest film, “High Flying Bird,” was shot entirely on an iPhone 8 and premiered on Netflix last month.)
<br/>“You can kind of make any damn thing right now, whether with your phone or with a DSLR,” he says. “The world is a young filmmaker’s oyster.”
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-02132019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Director Barry Jenkins discusses “If Beale Street Could Talk,” his third feature film, and the potential of today’s young filmmakers. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-on-set-02132019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Barry Jenkins on set with actors Dave Franco, Stephan James and KiKi Layne. Photo courtesy of Tatum Mangus / Annapurna Pictures." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-If-Beale-Street-Could-Talk-02132019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="“If Beale Street Could Talk” is the first English-language adaptation of James Baldwin, a prominent author on race relations in the US during the Civil Rights Era. Photo courtesy of Tatum Mangus / Annapurna Pictures." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-holding-MacBook-Pro-02132019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Filmmaker Barry Jenkins, featured in Apple’s Behind the Mac ad, exports the final cut of his Academy Award-winning film, “Moonlight.”" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-sence-from-If-Beale-Street-Could-Talk-02132019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="From left: Fonny played by Stephan James, Tish KiKi Layne and Daniel Brian Tyree Henry in Fonny’s apartment, moments before Daniel opens up about his incarceration in “If Beale Street Could Talk.” Photo courtesy of Tatum Mangus / Annapurna Pictures." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-06T10:15:43.610Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple names Deirdre O’Brien senior vice president of Retail and People]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/02/apple-names-deirdre-obrien-senior-vice-president-of-retail-and-people/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple names Deirdre O’Brien senior vice president of Retail + People <br/>Angela Ahrendts Plans April Departure After Five Successful Years<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced that Deirdre O’Brien is taking on new responsibilities for Apple’s retail and online stores in an expanded role as senior vice president of Retail + People, reporting to CEO Tim Cook. After five transformative years leading the company’s retail and online stores, Angela Ahrendts plans to depart Apple in April for new personal and professional pursuits.
<br/>In her expanded role, Deirdre will bring her three decades of Apple experience to lead the company’s global retail reach, focused on the connection between the customer and the people and processes that serve them. She will continue to lead the People team, overseeing all People-related functions, including talent development and Apple University, recruiting, employee relations and experience, business partnership, benefits, compensation, and inclusion and diversity. 
<br/>“At Apple, we believe our soul is our people, and Deirdre understands the qualities and strengths of our team better than anyone,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “For more than three decades, she has helped keep Apple focused on serving customers and enriching lives. She’s an exceptional leader and she’s been a vital partner to our retail teams around the world since the very beginning. I am thrilled to work alongside Deirdre in her new role, and I know our 70,000 retail employees will be, too.”
<br/>“People come to Apple to do the best work of their lives, and our retail teams show their passion every day, in every interaction, all around the world,” said Deirdre O’Brien, senior vice president of Retail + People. “It is the opportunity of a lifetime to work with, and learn from, such a talented, diverse and imaginative team. I am looking forward to this journey, and to continuing the important work of the People team in supporting all of Apple’s amazing employees.”
<br/>Apple today operates 35 online stores and 506 retail stores on five continents, staffed by teams who are dedicated to enriching lives and serving their communities. Every Apple retail store location offers innovative programs for customers, including Today at Apple, designed to unlock creativity, inspire learning and encourage connection.
<br/>“I want to thank Angela for inspiring and energising our teams over the past five years,” said Tim Cook. “She has been a positive, transformative force, both for Apple’s stores and the communities they serve. We all wish her the very best as she begins a new chapter.”
<br/>“The last five years have been the most stimulating, challenging and fulfilling of my career. Through the teams’ collective efforts, Retail has never been stronger or better positioned to make an even greater contribution for Apple,” said Angela Ahrendts, senior vice president of Retail. “I feel there is no better time to pass the baton to Deirdre, one of Apple’s strongest executives. I look forward to watching how this amazing team, under her leadership, will continue to change the world one person and one community at a time.”
<br/>Apple revolutionised personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Naomi Evans,Apple,nevans@apple.com,+44 (0) 203 284 6320<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/people/executives/Apple-Deirdre-OBrien-Apple-Park-02052019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple’s new Senior Vice President of Retail + People Deirdre O’Brien speaks to Apple employees on February 5, 2019." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/people/executives/Apple-Deirdre-OBrien-senior-vice-president-of-retail-and-people-02052019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Deirdre O’Brien, a 30-year Apple veteran, will lead Apple’s Retail and People teams." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-30T00:54:41.926Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple Reports First Quarter Results]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/apple-reports-first-quarter-results/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple Reports First Quarter Results<br/>Services, Mac and Wearables Set New All-Time Revenue Records<br/>EPS Reaches All-Time High at $4.18<br/>Cupertino, California — January 29, 2019 — Apple today announced financial results for its fiscal 2019 first quarter ended December 29, 2018. The Company posted quarterly revenue of $84.3 billion, a decline of 5 percent from the year-ago quarter, and quarterly earnings per diluted share of $4.18, up 7.5 percent. International sales accounted for 62 percent of the quarter’s revenue.
<br/>Revenue from iPhone® declined 15 percent from the prior year, while total revenue from all other products and services grew 19 percent. Services revenue reached an all-time high of $10.9 billion, up 19 percent over the prior year. Revenue from Mac® and Wearables, Home and Accessories also reached all-time highs, growing 9 percent and 33 percent, respectively, and revenue from iPad® grew 17 percent.
<br/>“While it was disappointing to miss our revenue guidance, we manage Apple for the long term, and this quarter’s results demonstrate that the underlying strength of our business runs deep and wide,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “Our active installed base of devices reached an all-time high of 1.4 billion in the first quarter, growing in each of our geographic segments. That’s a great testament to the satisfaction and loyalty of our customers, and it’s driving our Services business to new records thanks to our large and fast-growing ecosystem.”
<br/>“We generated very strong operating cash flow of $26.7 billion during the December quarter and set an all-time EPS record of $4.18,” said Luca Maestri, Apple’s CFO. “We returned over $13 billion to our investors during the quarter through dividends and share repurchases. Our net cash balance was $130 billion at the end of the quarter, and we continue to target a net cash neutral position over time.”
<br/>Apple is providing the following guidance for its fiscal 2019 second quarter:
<br/><ul style="list-style-position: inside;">
<li>revenue between $55 billion and $59 billion</li>
<li>gross margin between 37 percent and 38 percent</li>
<li>operating expenses between $8.5 billion and $8.6 billion</li>
<li>other income/(expense) of $300 million</li>
<li>tax rate of approximately 17 percent</li>
</ul>
<br/>Apple’s board of directors has declared a cash dividend of $0.73 per share of the Company’s common stock. The dividend is payable on February 14, 2019 to shareholders of record as of the close of business on February 11, 2019.
<br/>Apple will provide live streaming of its Q1 2019 financial results conference call beginning at 2:00 p.m. PST on January 29, 2019 at <a href="https://www.apple.com/investor/earnings-call/" target="_blank">www.apple.com/investor/earnings-call/</a>. This webcast will also be available for replay for approximately two weeks thereafter.
<br/>Apple periodically provides information for investors on its corporate website, <a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank">apple.com</a>, and its investors relations website, <a href="https://investor.apple.com/" target="_blank">investor.apple.com</a>. This includes press releases and other information about financial performance, reports filed or furnished with the SEC, information on corporate governance and details related to its annual meeting of shareholders.
<br/>This press release contains forward-looking statements, within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These forward-looking statements include without limitation those about the Company’s estimated revenue, gross margin, operating expenses, other income/(expense), tax rate, and plans for return of capital. These statements involve risks and uncertainties, and actual results may differ. Risks and uncertainties include without limitation: the effect of global and regional economic conditions on the Company's business, including effects on purchasing decisions by consumers and businesses; the ability of the Company to compete in markets that are highly competitive and subject to rapid technological change; the ability of the Company to manage frequent introductions and transitions of products and services, including delivering to the marketplace, and stimulating customer demand for, new products, services and technological innovations on a timely basis; the effect that shifts in the mix of products and services and in the geographic, currency or channel mix, component cost increases, price competition, or the introduction of new products, including new products with higher cost structures, could have on the Company’s gross margin; the dependency of the Company on the performance of distributors of the Company's products, including cellular network carriers and other resellers; the inventory and other asset risks associated with the Company’s need to order, or commit to order, product components in advance of customer orders; the continued availability on acceptable terms, or at all, of certain components, services and new technologies essential to the Company's business, including components and technologies that may only be available from single or limited sources; the dependency of the Company on manufacturing and logistics services provided by third parties, many of which are located outside of the US and which may affect the quality, quantity or cost of products manufactured or services rendered to the Company; the effect of product and services design and manufacturing defects on the Company’s financial performance and reputation; the dependency of the Company on third-party intellectual property and digital content, which may not be available to the Company on commercially reasonable terms or at all; the dependency of the Company on support from third-party software developers to develop and maintain software applications and services for the Company’s products; the impact of unfavourable legal proceedings, such as a potential finding that the Company has infringed on the intellectual property rights of others; the impact of changes to laws and regulations that affect the Company’s activities, including the Company’s ability to offer products or services to customers in different regions; the ability of the Company to manage risks associated with its international activities, including complying with laws and regulations affecting the Company’s international operations; the ability of the Company to manage risks associated with the Company’s retail stores; the ability of the Company to manage risks associated with the Company’s investments in new business strategies and acquisitions; the impact on the Company's business and reputation from information technology system failures, network disruptions or losses or unauthorised access to, or release of, confidential information; the ability of the Company to comply with laws and regulations regarding data protection; the continued service and availability of key executives and employees; political events, international trade disputes, war, terrorism, natural disasters, public health issues, and other business interruptions that could disrupt supply or delivery of, or demand for, the Company’s products; financial risks, including risks relating to currency fluctuations, credit risks and fluctuations in the market value of the Company’s investment portfolio; and changes in tax rates and exposure to additional tax liabilities. More information on these risks and other potential factors that could affect the Company’s financial results is included in the Company’s filings with the SEC, including in the “Risk Factors” and “Management’s Discussion and Analysis of Financial Condition and Results of Operations” sections of the Company’s most recently filed periodic reports on Form 10-K and Form 10-Q and subsequent filings. The Company assumes no obligation to update any forward-looking statements or information, which speak as of their respective dates.
<br/>Apple revolutionised personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contact <br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>Investor Relations Contacts<br/>Nancy Paxton,Apple,paxton1@apple.com,+1 (408) 974-5420<br/>Matt Blake,Apple ,mattblake@apple.com,+1 (408) 974-7406<br/>© 2019 Apple Inc. All rights reserved. Apple and the Apple logo are trademarks of Apple Inc. Other company and product names may be trademarks of their respective owners.<br/>
]]></content></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-29T18:09:48.280Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple announces new Today at Apple sessions]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/apple-announces-new-today-at-apple-sessions/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple announces new Today at Apple sessions<br/>Over 50 New Sessions Now Available<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced a new Today at Apple release with sessions in three new and expanded formats — Skills, Walks and Labs — which offer hands-on group sessions focused on photography, video, music, coding, app development, art and design and more. The new sessions are free at every Apple Store worldwide and allow visitors to find the right session for their interests and skill level in order to unlock their creativity, inspire learning and encourage connection.
<br/>Since the launch of Today at Apple in 2017, Apple has held over 18,000 free sessions a week attended by millions of participants around the world. This newest release expands on the most popular types of Today at Apple sessions, Walks and Labs, providing visitors even more opportunities to get more out of their products, find inspiration in their community and discover guidance from world-class creators.
<br/>“Since the beginning, Today at Apple has been about educating and inspiring the communities we serve. These new sessions are an opportunity to unlock the creative potential in all of our customers,” said Angela Ahrendts, Apple’s senior vice president of Retail. “There is a session for everyone at Today at Apple and we can’t wait to see what you will create.”<br />

<br/>Three Today at Apple session formats facilitate learning and creativity:
<br/><ul>
<li><strong>Skills</strong>&nbsp;are meant for those interested in learning new creative techniques to go further with our products, such as making a quick video with the Clips app or editing photos on iPhone. New Skills sessions include Notes and Chords with GarageBand, Sketching Ideas in Notes, Photo Editing Techniques and more.</li>
</ul>
<br/><ul>
<li><strong>Walks</strong> invite customers to venture outside of the store with a Creative Pro, where they will explore their surroundings, connect with their community and put new skills to use across passions like photography, music or health.&nbsp;New Walks include Capturing Cinematic Shots, Creating Soundscapes with GarageBand and a Health and Fitness Walk, Staying Motivated co-created with fitness expert Jeanette Jenkins.</li>
</ul>
<br/><ul>
<li><strong>Labs</strong> help customers experiment with creative techniques and complete the session with the beginning of a project. Many Labs have been co-created with world-renowned artists and makers. Building on the success of Labs with Florence Welch and photographer Chase Jarvis, skilled customers can find inspiration in new Labs like Beat Making with Swizz Beatz, Small Screen Magic with Zach King and Drawing Treehouses with Foster + Partners.</li>
</ul>
<br/>Today at Apple is also a great resource for families and kids of all ages interested in photography, coding, art and design and more. Labs like Fun Family Portraits, the Sphero Robot Obstacle Challenge and Make Your Own Emoji are built specifically to educate and spark creativity in younger visitors.<br />

<br/>Today at Apple includes sessions designed specifically for educators so teachers can learn new ways of bringing technology into their classroom, with Labs like App Design and Prototyping and Class Projects with Clips, based on the Everyone Can Code and Everyone Can Create curriculums.
<br/>To further enrich the Today at Apple experience in every store, Apple is upgrading the existing fleet of stores with design elements that greatly increase the store’s Today at Apple sessions and capacity. These upgrades include the addition of The Forum, an area of the store with a large video wall and seating, serving as a meeting place for the local community and home for Today at Apple. Some stores will add Avenues and, where possible, a grove of trees with integrated seating.<br />

<br/>To find and register for a new session, visit <a href="https://www.apple.com/today/" target="_blank">www.apple.com/today</a> or the Sessions tab in the Apple Store App.
<br/>Apple revolutionised personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-today-at-Apple-sessions-Photo-lab-creating-photo-essays-01292019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="New Today at Apple sessions expand the possibilities for participants to find inspiration and create something new. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Photo-walk-framing-architecture-01292019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Photo Walks encourage visitors to find inspiration in their communities." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Art-skills-getting-started-Procreate-01292019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="At Skills sessions, attendees can learn and practice new creative techniques. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Skills-01292019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A sample of the new Today at Apple lineup, featuring hands-on Skills, Walks and Labs sessions." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Walks-01292019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A sample of the new Today at Apple lineup, featuring hands-on Skills, Walks and Labs sessions." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Labs-01292019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A sample of the new Today at Apple lineup, featuring hands-on Skills, Walks and Labs sessions." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Music-lab-teachers-telling-stories-Garageband-01292019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Labs take place in the Forum, the heart of the store which serves as a meeting place for the local community and home for Today at Apple." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-29T10:36:43.343Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple Entrepreneur Camp kicks off as app developer earnings hit new record]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/apple-entrepreneur-camp-kicks-off-as-app-developer-earnings-hit-new-record/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple Entrepreneur Camp kicks off as app developer earnings hit new record<br/>Inaugural Session Provides Unprecedented Access to Apple Labs, Engineers, Business and Marketing Expertise<br><br>
App Developer Earnings Reach $120B Since 2008 App Store Launch<br/>Today, Apple opens its doors to 11 female-founded app development companies for the inaugural session of Entrepreneur Camp. The program is designed to provide female app creators with the tools needed to thrive in today’s global app economy. Since the App Store launched in 2008, developers have earned $120 billion, with more than a quarter of that in the past year alone.
<br/>An industry first, Entrepreneur Camp is a two-week immersive hands-on technology lab where participants work one-on-one with Apple experts and engineers to significantly accelerate their apps. The program also includes sessions on design, technology and App Store marketing, as well as ongoing guidance and support from an Apple Developer Relations representative. The curriculum will help developers take advantage of cutting-edge Apple technologies, including optimising for the A12 Bionic chip, integrating Core ML, building new experiences with ARKit and more. Each participating company will also receive two tickets to WWDC and complementary membership to the Apple Developer Program for one year.
<br/>“The App Store is the new digital Main Street, and creative developers are tapping into the vast potential of the global app economy.”
<br/>“In the past, starting a small business often meant having to invest in overhead, inventory or retail space. Today, a world of opportunity opens up with some coding skills and an entrepreneurial spirit,” said Esther Hare, Apple’s senior director, Worldwide Developer Marketing and executive sponsor, Women@Apple. “The App Store is the new digital Main Street, and creative developers are tapping into the vast potential of the global app economy. We hope that this program helps to inspire women around the world to learn to code, join the iOS development community and share in the thriving app economy.”
<br/>The apps selected for the first session of Entrepreneur Camp are: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/bites/id1285503275?mt=8" target="_blank">Bites</a> by Warehouse Apps LLC; Camille by Ohhh, Inc.; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cuco-meds-pill-reminder/id1202953264?mt=8" target="_blank">CUCO: Lembrete de Medicamentos</a> by CUCO Health; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/deepr-dating-app/id1441236131?mt=8" target="_blank">Deepr</a>&nbsp;by Mental Mobile, LLC; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/defekt/id1367644508?mt=8" target="_blank">D’efekt</a> by Tatevik Gasparyan, Nané Toumanian and Vahagn Khachikyan; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hopscotch-coding-for-kids/id617098629?mt=8" target="_blank">Hopscotch</a> by Hopscotch Technologies; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/lactapp/id1040787494?mt=8" target="_blank">LactApp</a> by LactApp Women Health; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pureple-outfit-planner/id628106373?mt=8" target="_blank">Pureple</a>&nbsp;by Iceclip LLC; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/statues-of-the-la-paz-malec%C3%B3n/id1384303234?mt=8" target="_blank">Statues of the La Paz Malecón</a> by Estudio Chispa; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/weparent-top-coparenting-app/id1441850251?mt=8" target="_blank">WeParent</a> by FamTerra Inc.; and <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/seneca-connect/id1350551544?mt=8" target="_blank">Seneca Connect</a> by Seneca Women.
<br/>Entrepreneur Camp will hold sessions on a quarterly basis, with up to 20 app companies accepted for each round. To be admitted to the program, app-driven businesses must be female founded, co-founded or led, and have at least one woman on the product development team. They must also have a working app or prototype. For more information on Apple Entrepreneur Camp or to apply, visit <a href="https://developer.apple.com/entrepreneur-camp/" target="_blank">developer.apple.com/entrepreneur-camp</a>.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-kicks-off-01282019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="From left: Livia Cunha, Nané Toumanian, and Tatevik Gasparyan are part of the inaugural class of Apple Entrepreneur Camp attendees arriving at Apple Park." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Kim-Azzarelli-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Kim Azzarelli, co-founder, Seneca Connect " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Suejung-Huh-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Suejung B. Huh, founder, Camille" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Livia-Cunha-01292019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Livia Cunha, CUCO: Lembrete de Medicamentos " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Roza-Ferdowsmakan-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Roza Ferdowsmakan, founder, Bites " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Elena-Krasnoperova-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Elena Krasnoperova, founder of WeParent" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Zhuo-Song-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Zhuo Song, developer, WeParent" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Cindy-Yates-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Cindy Yates, founder, Statues of the La Paz Malecón" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Fabiola-Werneck-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Fabiola Werneck, CTO, CUCO: Lembrete de Medicamentos  " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Enric-Roura-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Enric Roura, CEO, LactApp " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Alvar-Hernandez-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Àlvar Hernández, AI developer, LactApp" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Samantha-John-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Samantha John, CEO and co-founder, Hopscotch" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Nane-Toumanian-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Nané Toumanian, CEO and designer, D’efekt" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Maria-Berruezo-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Maria Berruezo, co-founder, LactApp" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Jung-Jin-Kang-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Jung Jin Kang, designer, Camille" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Tatevilk-Gasparyan-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Tatevik Gasparyan, founder and CTO, D’efekt " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Rocio-Tovar-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Rocío Tovar, CTO, LactApp" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Renee-Olson-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Renee Olson, founder, Deepr" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Nazan-Kurt-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Nazan Kurt, founder, Pureple" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Rodrigo-Tello-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Rodrigo Tello, designer, Hopscotch" type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-24T18:01:47.128Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[The Mac App Store welcomes Office 365]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/the-mac-app-store-welcomes-office-365/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[The Mac App Store welcomes Office 365<br/>Today, Office 365 is available for the first time on the Mac App Store, making it easier than ever for Mac users to download Word, Outlook, Excel, PowerPoint, OneNote and the whole suite of Microsoft’s popular apps. Users can also purchase a subscription for <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app-bundle/id1450038993?mt=12" target="_blank">Office 365</a> from within the apps, so they can get up and running instantly.
<br/>Office 365 for Mac has been designed specifically to support features that are unique to the Mac experience — features like Dark Mode and Continuity Camera in macOS, as well as the MacBook Pro Touch Bar and the Mac’s industry-leading Trackpad.
<br/>“We are excited to welcome Microsoft Office 365 to the all new Mac App Store in macOS Mojave,” said Phil Schiller, Apple’s senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing. “Apple and Microsoft have worked together to bring great Office productivity to Mac users from the very beginning. Now, with Office 365 on the Mac App Store, it's easier than ever to get the latest and best version of Office 365 for Mac, iPad and iPhone.”
<br/>“We are excited to announce that today Office 365 is arriving in the Mac App Store,” said Jared Spataro, corporate vice president at Microsoft. “We have worked closely with Apple to provide Mac users with the very best productivity experience — one that offers everything they know and love about Office through an experience uniquely designed for the Mac.”
<br/>In business, as at home, employees want access to the best devices and apps to do their work. With Office 365 on the Mac App Store, these apps can now be easily distributed to employees using <a href="http://business.apple.com" target="_blank">Apple Business Manager</a>, a central dashboard where IT can deploy devices, apps and licenses. Now IT can quickly enable employees to get to work with their favourite Office tools across Mac, iPad and iPhone, with great new features designed specifically for Apple devices.
<br/>About the Mac App Store
<br/>The Mac App Store is the single largest catalog of Mac apps in the world. Newly redesigned this past year, the Mac App Store features a new look and rich editorial content for a more enjoyable experience when finding great, new apps for the Mac. Like the iOS App Store, the new Mac App Store celebrates apps, games, businesses and developers with an all-new Discover tab featuring compelling stories, in-depth interviews, helpful tips, collections of must-have apps and more. Users can also explore new Create, Work, Play and Develop tabs to find the perfect app for a specific project or purpose — from music, video and photography apps to business utilities and games.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Office-365-now-available-on-mac-app-store-01242019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Microsoft Office 365 is now available on the Mac App Store for the first time." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Office-365-now-available-OneNote-mac-app-store-screen-01242019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Office 365 arrives on the Mac App Store following its recent redesign, featuring an all-new look and rich editorial content." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Office-365-now-available-PowerPoint-app-screen-01242019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Office 365 apps, including PowerPoint, are specially designed to support the unique Mac experience." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-22T18:31:51.894Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Share your best photos shot on iPhone]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/share-your-best-photos-shot-on-iphone/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Share your best photos shot on iPhone<br/>Apple is kicking off 2019 by celebrating the most stunning photographs captured on iPhone, the world’s most popular camera, by inviting iPhone users to submit their best shots.
<br/>From January 22 to February 7, Apple is looking for outstanding photographs for a Shot on iPhone Challenge. A panel of judges will review worldwide submissions and select 10 winning photos, to be announced in February. The winning photos will be featured on billboards in select cities, Apple retail stores and online.
<br/>iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span>, iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span> Max, and iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span> bring innovations to photography, from sophisticated portraits with an adjustable depth of field, to Smart HDR which leverages multiple technologies — like faster sensors, an enhanced ISP and advanced algorithms — to bring more highlight and shadow detail to photos.<br/>Meet the Judges
<br/><strong>Pete Souza (US)</strong><br />
Pete was the chief official White House photographer for President Obama. His book, “Obama: An Intimate Portrait,” debuted as the #1 New York Times bestseller and is one of the best-selling photography books of all time.
<br/><strong>Austin Mann (US)</strong><br>
Austin is an iPhone photographer, filmmaker and creative who’s traveled around the world and has worked with numerous non-profit organisations to help better cast their vision worldwide. Austin has published iPhone photography reviews in outlets including National Geographic and CNN over the years.
<br/><strong>Annet de Graaf (Netherlands)</strong><br />
Graaf is a travel photographer who uses iPhone exclusively for her craft. She’s the author of two iPhone photography books: “Morning Amsterdam” and the upcoming “GO d’Azur,” the latter of which was shot entirely on iPhone 8 Plus. She’s taken portraits of Syrian ballet dancer Ahmad Joudeh as well as the late mayor of Amsterdam, Eberhard van der Laan.
<br/><strong>Luísa Dörr (Brazil)</strong><br />
Luísa is a photographer based in Brazil who rose to fame after she photographed TIME’s Firsts issue exclusively on iPhone. TIME won Documentary Project of the Year for the story in the prestigious Pictures of the Year International.
<br/><strong>Chen Man (China)</strong><br>
Chen is a Chinese contemporary visual artist and entrepreneur who created a unique visual language that revolutionised fashion photography in China. Her work has been permanently collected at the Victoria and Albert Museum in London and the Asian Art Museum in San Francisco. She also co-founded an Internet company called Vnision that developed photography-based social apps including Bigshot.
<br/><strong>Phil Schiller</strong><br />
Phil has helped Apple reinvent mobile phones with iPhone. A keen photographer, Phil helps with efforts in developing breakthrough camera technology as senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing.<br />

<br/><strong>Kaiann Drance</strong><br />
Kaiann works with talented teams at Apple to deliver products that put great photographic tools in the hands of many, including the first iPod touch with a camera and multiple generations of iPhone, in her role as senior director in Worldwide Product Marketing.
<br/><strong>Brooks Kraft</strong><br />
Brooks is a professional photographer and worked in editorial and commercial photography prior to joining Apple. He was a contributing photographer at TIME magazine, where he covered the White House during the Bush and Obama administrations, as well as seven presidential campaigns.
<br/><strong>Sebastien Marineau-Mes</strong><br />
Sebastien brings over 20 years of software development knowledge to iPhone in his role as vice president of Software at Apple. His focus on advanced photography features includes innovations like Smart HDR and Portrait mode with Depth Control.
<br/><strong>Jon McCormack</strong><br>
Jon is an accomplished photographer who currently leads Apple’s camera software team. Jon’s images have been published by international organisations including TIME, The New York Times, UNESCO, The Nature Conservancy, Africa Geographic and others.
<br/><strong>Arem Duplessis</strong><br />
Arem works closely with some of the most accomplished photographers in the world in his role as the director of photography in Apple’s marketing team. He previously served as design director of The New York Times Magazine for nearly a decade.
<br/>Submitting Your Best Shot
<br/>Post your best photo taken on iPhone to Instagram or Twitter with the #ShotOniPhone hashtag to participate in the the Shot on iPhone Challenge. Weibo users can participate as well using #ShotOniPhone#. In the image caption, note which model was used. Alternatively, you can also submit the photo in its highest resolution to shotoniphone@apple.com with the file format ‘firstname<em>lastname</em>iphonemodel.’ Photos can be straight from the camera, edited through Apple’s editing tools in the Photos app or with third-party software. Submissions for photos begins at 12:01 a.m. PST on January 22 and ends at 11:59 p.m. PST on February 7. You must be 18 years of age or older to participate, and this challenge is not open to Apple employees or their immediate families.
<br/>Ten winning photos will be featured on Apple Newsroom, Apple’s Instagram channels, <a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank">apple.com</a>, in Apple retail stores, Apple WeChat, Apple Twitter accounts, Apple Weibo accounts and billboards around the world. Winners will be notified on or about February 26, 2019.
<br/>If you’re submitting your photo on social media, you must make your photos public. Ineligible submissions include photos that violate or infringe upon another person’s rights, including but not limited to copyright, trademark, privacy, publicity or any other intellectual property rights or civil rights; contain sexually explicit, nude, obscene, violent or other objectionable or inappropriate content; or in any way disparage Apple or any other person or party.
<br/>You retain your rights to your photograph; however, by submitting your photo, you grant Apple a royalty-free, world-wide, irrevocable, non-exclusive license for one year to use, modify, publish, display, distribute, create derivative works from and reproduce the photo on Apple Newsroom, <a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank">apple.com</a>, Apple Twitter accounts, Apple Instagram (@Apple), in Apple retail stores, Apple Weibo, Apple WeChat, on billboards and any Apple internal exhibitions. Any photograph reproduced will include a photographer credit. If your photo is selected to be featured on a billboard, you further agree to grant Apple exclusive commercial use of the photo for the life of the license. Apple believes strongly that artists should be compensated for their work. Photographers who shoot the final 10 winning photos will receive a licensing fee for use of such photos on billboards and other Apple marketing channels.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/Shot-on-iPhone-Challenge-Announcement-Woman-in-front-of-Petra_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Shot on iPhone 7 by Erdem Summak." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/Shot-on-iPhone-Challenge-Announcement-Forest_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Shot on iPhone 6s by Mariko Klug." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/Shot-on-iPhone-Challenge-Announcement-Swimming-in-water_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Shot on iPhone 6 by Mandy Blake." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-21T15:05:43.880Z]]></updated><category term="FEATURE"/><title><![CDATA[Out of a culture of giving, a world of difference]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/out-of-a-culture-of-giving-a-world-of-difference/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Out of a culture of giving, a world of difference<br/>How Apple Volunteers are Helping Transform Lives<br/>Fourteen-year-old Michael Normoyle jumps out of his chair to write his cipher on the board: <em>ZLANZRVFZVPUNRY.</em>
<br/>The rest of the class starts furiously scribbling at their desks, hoping to be the first to solve the puzzle.
<br/>In coding class at Terence MacSwiney School in Cork, Ireland, things tend to get very competitive among this group of fourteen and fifteen year olds. That’s especially true for Normoyle and classmates Seán Harris and Michael McGlue — all three are vying to be named the year’s standout coding student.
<br/>The programme is part of a special initiative made possible by Apple volunteers from the company’s nearby Cork campus. Once a week, more than a dozen volunteers visit the school to help teach coding, drawing, photography, music and video. Since the programme began three years ago, the school — one of the most economically disadvantaged in Ireland — and its students have been transformed.
<br/>It’s one of thousands of organisations where Apple employees volunteer their time. And for every hour an employee gives, or dollar they donate, Apple provides matching funds for both. In 2018, that added up to more than a quarter of a million hours volunteered and more than $125 million donated to organisations around the world.
<br/>That includes China, where Apple is one of the only global companies matching employee donations. Thirty-two Chinese charitable organisations are now eligible to receive funds, including the China Foundation for Poverty Alleviation, which aided more than 175,000 people across 24 provinces with disaster relief and preparedness in 2018 alone.&nbsp; &nbsp;
<br/>“You have to create hope, no matter what context you work in. Sometimes you need a bit of help with that.”
<br/>All told, since its inception eight years ago, Apple’s Giving programme has become a powerful force for global good, raising more than $365 million for nonprofits around the world. Though if you ask the people whose lives have been changed by these efforts, they’ll tell you that the benefit can be measured in so much more than dollars and cents. 
<br/>“We have a lot of students that have the odds stacked against them,” says Terence MacSwiney’s Principal Phil O’Flynn. “But this programme has helped nurture them, and we’ve discovered talents that we never knew they had.”
<br/>Before they started the programme, Normoyle, Harris and McGlue never expected their future careers to involve coding. All three would be the first in their families to complete a post-secondary degree, something their teacher Linda Cagney and Principal O’Flynn say is now well within their reach.
<br/>“You have to create hope, no matter what context you work in,” says O’Flynn. “Sometimes you need a bit of help with that, and that’s what this programme does — it lifts the school.”
<br/>Back in coding class, students are still trying to decipher Normoyle’s cipher. Eventually, someone shouts out: “My name is Michael.” 
<br/>He smiles, and confirms that’s exactly right.
<br/><center><em>*</em></center>
<br/>Lauren Cook, 24, was a senior at San Jose State University in 2017, working four jobs to make ends meet when she saw a flyer advertising a Second Harvest food pantry at the school. She left with more than bags full of fresh produce.
<br/>“Second Harvest helped me become the person I am today — sorry, I’m getting a little emotional,” says Cook, through tears. “It meant I had to work only one job, and it allowed me to focus on being a college student.”
<br/>Since the Great Recession in 2008, the number of people served each month by Second Harvest Food Bank in Santa Clara and San Mateo Counties, which include most of Silicon Valley, has seen a 47 percent jump — from an average of 175,000 to 260,000. In 2018 alone that translated to almost 55 million meals.
<br/>Apple’s history of volunteering with Second Harvest goes back to 2000. Last year, its employees spent almost 3000 hours sorting and distributing food, which makes the food bank one of the largest recipients of Apple volunteer hours in the US.&nbsp;
<br/>“What’s so important about this partnership is that we have Apple volunteers that we can depend on,” said Second Harvest CEO Leslie Bacho. “That long-term commitment makes it possible to try new things and innovate, which includes our food pantries at colleges. It’s what gives me hope that if there’s anywhere in the country we can solve hunger, it would be here.”
<br/><center><em>*</em></center>
<br/>When Samuel Snowe, 29, opened the package containing his chest binder, he was surprised to find something else.
<br/>“Be the person you want to be,” the note began. “Loving yourself is the first step. Thank you for being your amazing self.”
<br/>It was signed only, ‘Megan.’ Snowe was overcome with emotion — those twenty one words reminded him he wasn’t alone.&nbsp;
<br/>In 2009, Aydian Dowling came out as transgender, but medical insurance wouldn’t cover his transition. He eventually raised enough funds on his own and with the support of friends, but the negative experience left him wanting to help others. Two years ago, he co-founded Point of Pride, whose mission statement is “to benefit trans people in need through gender-affirming support programmes that empower them to live more authentically.”
<br/>That includes the organisation’s apparel programme, which has sent out more than 3500 free chest binders to people around the world including Snowe, along with a personal note of encouragement.
<br/>The idea to include a note began when the organisation linked up with Apple employee Liz Byrne, who now sits on Point of Pride’s board. Liz received a letter of encouragement from a close friend while going through a difficult time in high school. Liz has since organised almost 20 writing sessions at Apple’s Cupertino, Austin and Sacramento campuses, attended by hundreds of employees.&nbsp;
<br/>For Snowe, receiving the free binder was essential, but he credits the note with even more. 
<br/>“Being transgender, there’s a lot of moments where you don’t feel like you deserve to be alive — like you’re less of a human,” says Snowe. “And things like this remind us that we’re still human, we’re still alive, we’re still people, and we’re important to somebody.” 
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-student-Ericka-Lingwood-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Terence MacSwiney School student Ericka Lingwood has developed her animation skills as part of the Apple volunteer programme." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-student-Micheal-Normoyle-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Terence MacSwiney School student Michael Normoyle writes his cipher on the board in coding class, while Apple volunteer Pavel Zizka looks on." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-students-in-many-subjects-01211019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple volunteers work with students across a range of subjects, including photography." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Principal-Phil-O-Flynn-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Terence MacSwiney School Principal Phil O’Flynn has seen a dramatic change in her students since the Apple volunteer initiative began." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Teacher-Linda-Cagney-assists-students-in-ciphers-coding-class-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Terence MacSwiney teacher Linda Cagney assists students Michael McGlue and Seán Harris as they work solving ciphers in coding class." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Second-Harvest-Lauren-Cook-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Lauren Cook credits Second Harvest with giving her the chance to focus on college and her future." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Second-Harvest-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple volunteers sort oranges at Second Harvest Food Bank in San Jose, California." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-letter-of-encouragement-from-Point-of-Pride-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="An example of a letter of encouragement from Point of Pride." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Point-of-Pride-letter-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="An example of a letter of encouragement from Point of Pride." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Point-of-Pride-note-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="An example of a letter of encouragement from Point of Pride." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Aydian-Dowling-co-founded-Point-of-Pride-to-help-trans-community-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Aydian Dowling co-founded Point of Pride to help other members of the trans community." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Liz-Byrne-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Liz Byrne has helped organise letter writing sessions at Apple that are open to all employees." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-note-Liz-Byrne-Point-of-Pride-letter-writing-program_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The note that Liz Byrne received from a friend in high school that became the inspiration for Point of Pride’s letter writing programme." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-21T12:08:56.613Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Everyone Can Create now available in more European languages ]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/everyone-can-create-now-available-in-more-european-languages/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Everyone Can Create now available in more European languages <br/>Designed to Unleash Students’ Creativity, Free Guides Now Available in German, French, Spanish and Italian <br/>Apple’s Everyone Can Create curriculum is now available in German, French, Spanish and Italian on Apple Books. The free project guides for iPad, designed to help students develop and communicate ideas through music, video, drawing and photos, will also be available in Swedish and Dutch this spring.
<br/>Since the launch of Everyone Can Create four months ago, teachers and parents across Europe have downloaded Everyone Can Create resources nearly 100,000 times integrating creativity into lessons and assignments that help students develop new skills and new ways to express themselves throughout their school day.
<br/>Everyone Can Create builds on the success of Apple’s intuitive Everyone Can Code curriculum, which is already being taught in schools around the world, including hundreds of European institutions. Coding has transformed the global economy and created millions of jobs, and the curriculum, which uses Apple’s easy-to-use programming language Swift, allows all students to learn and prepare for the workforce.
<br/>“Creativity is at the heart of everything we do at Anson Primary and Everyone Can Create has helped us push those boundaries even further,” said Simon Pile, assistant head of Anson Primary School, London. “Using a combination of the project guides we’ve created richer and deeper learning experiences for students in subjects across the curriculum, bringing better understanding of the concepts being taught.”
<br/>Add Creativity to Every Subject
<br/>The Everyone Can Create curriculum was developed in collaboration with educators and artists to allow teachers to easily incorporate creativity into their existing lesson plans in any subject, including literature, math, science, history, humanities and coding.
<br/>“Everyone Can Create has given me confidence in front of my students in areas of teaching, such as drawing, which I would not otherwise have had,” said Zainab Patel, assistant headteacher of Olive Tree Primary School, Manchester.
<br/>Apple and Teachers
<br/>With a 40 year legacy in education, Apple has transformed the way teachers teach and students learn, with powerful products, curricula and technologies that engage and inspire everyone in the classroom. Using iPad, Mac and a variety of educational apps, students have a truly personal learning experience with the power and freedom to bring ideas to life.
<br/>Apple Teacher, Apple’s free self-paced learning programme designed to support educators in using Apple products for teaching and learning, is now used by more than 63,000 teachers across Europe to build skills on iPad and Mac that directly apply to activities with their students. Starting today, Apple Teacher is available to even more educators including those speaking Italian, Spanish and Swedish, alongside English, French and German.
<br/>Nearly 200,000 education apps are available in the App Store today including apps like Apple’s Classroom and Schoolwork that give teachers the ability to create and share assignments, collaborate and view student progress, and tailor instructions to individual student needs, all in one place.
<br/><strong>Availability</strong>
<br/><ul>
<li>Everyone Can Create is now available for anyone to download everywhere Apple Books is available.</li>
</ul>
<br/><ul>
<li>Apple Stores are using Everyone Can Create in Today at Apple sessions. In 2018 across Europe, more than 40,000 students and teachers attended sessions including tutorials on art and design, photo and video, and music.</li>
</ul>
<br/><ul>
<li>Becoming an Apple Teacher is fun and easy. By signing up using a personal Apple ID, teachers gain access to the Apple Teacher Learning Center to build skills, collect badges and earn recognition as an Apple Teacher.</li>
</ul>
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Everyone-Can-Create-available-in-more-European-languages-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Everyone Can Create teaches students to develop and communicate ideas through drawing, photography, video and music." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/everyone-can-create-ipad-english-drawing-screen-01212019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Designed to unleash students’ creativity, the free guides are now available in German, French, Spanish and Italian." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/everyone-can-create-ipad-french-music-screen-01212019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Designed to unleash students’ creativity, the free guides are now available in German, French, Spanish and Italian." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/everyone-can-create-ipad-german-video-screen-01212019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Designed to unleash students’ creativity, the free guides are now available in German, French, Spanish and Italian." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/everyone-can-create-ipad-english-drawing-screen-2-01212019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Teachers and parents across Europe have downloaded Everyone Can Create nearly 100,000 times since launch." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/everyone-can-create-ipad-french-photo-screen-2-01212019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Teachers and parents across Europe have downloaded Everyone Can Create nearly 100,000 times since launch." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/everyone-can-create-ipad-german-photo-screen-2-01212019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Teachers and parents across Europe have downloaded Everyone Can Create nearly 100,000 times since launch." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Everyone-Can-Create-teacher-on-iPad-01212019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The free guides help ignite creativity by giving teachers fun and meaningful ways to bring these skills into any lesson, topic or assignment." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Everyone-Can-Create-student-drawing-on-iPad-01212019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Everyone Can Create was developed in collaboration with educators and artists to allow teachers to easily incorporate creativity into their existing lesson plans in any subject." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-03T17:05:41.901Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[App Store caps record-breaking 2018 with blockbuster holiday week]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/app-store-caps-record-breaking-2018-with-blockbuster-holiday-week/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[App Store caps record-breaking 2018 with blockbuster holiday week<br/>Customers Spent $1.22B During the 2018 Holiday and Kicked off 2019 With a New Single-Day Record on New Year’s Day<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced that App Store customers worldwide set new spending records over the holidays, wrapping up a record-breaking year. App Store spending topped $1.22 billion between Christmas Eve and New Year’s Eve. Customers also spent over $322 million on New Year’s Day 2019 alone, setting a new single-day record.
<br/>“The App Store had a record-breaking holiday week and New Year's Day. The holiday week was our biggest week ever with more than $1.22 billion spent on apps and games, and New Year’s Day set a new single-day record at more than $322 million,” said Phil Schiller, Apple’s senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing. “Thanks to the inspiring work of our talented developers and the support of our incredible customers around the world, the App Store finished off an outstanding 2018 and kicked off 2019 with a bang.”
<br/>Apple announced Wednesday that the App Store helped drive Services revenue to an all-time record in the holiday quarter. Apple services set new all-time records in multiple categories, including the App Store, Apple Music, Cloud Services, Apple Pay and the App Store’s search ad business.<br />

<br/>Gaming and self-care were the most popular categories of app downloads and subscriptions during the holidays. Globally, multiplayer games including Fortnite and PUBG were among the top downloaded games over the holidays, along with Brawl Stars, Asphalt 9 and Monster Strike. Productivity, Health &amp; Fitness and Education apps are already capturing the attention of customers in the first few days of the year with 1Password, Sweat and Lumosity&nbsp;charting in their respective categories.<br>

<br/>Apple revolutionised personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.<br />

<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/app-store/App-Store-caps-record-breaking-2018-with-blockbuster-holiday-week-01032019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Customers spent over $322 million in the App Store on New Year’s Day 2019 alone, setting a new single-day record." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-03T07:20:45.419Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Letter from Tim Cook to Apple investors]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2019/01/letter-from-tim-cook-to-apple-investors/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Letter from Tim Cook to Apple investors<br/>January 2, 2019<br>

<br/>To Apple investors:
<br/>Today we are revising our guidance for Apple’s fiscal 2019 first quarter, which ended on December 29. We now expect the following:
<br/><ul>
<li>Revenue of approximately $84 billion</li>
<li>Gross margin of approximately 38 percent</li>
<li>Operating expenses of approximately $8.7 billion</li>
<li>Other income/(expense) of approximately $550 million</li>
<li>Tax rate of approximately 16.5 percent before discrete items</li>
</ul>
<br/>We expect the number of shares used in computing diluted EPS to be approximately 4.77 billion.
<br/>Based on these estimates, our revenue will be lower than our original guidance for the quarter, with other items remaining broadly in line with our guidance. 
<br/>While it will be a number of weeks before we complete and report our final results, we wanted to get some preliminary information to you now. Our final results may differ somewhat from these preliminary estimates. 
<br/>When we discussed our Q1 guidance with you about 60 days ago, we knew the first quarter would be impacted by both macroeconomic and Apple-specific factors. Based on our best estimates of how these would play out, we predicted that we would report slight revenue growth year-over-year for the quarter. As you may recall, we discussed four factors:
<br/>First, we knew the different timing of our iPhone launches would affect our year-over-year compares. Our top models, iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span> and iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span> Max, shipped in Q4’18—placing the channel fill and early sales in that quarter, whereas last year iPhone X shipped in Q1’18, placing the channel fill and early sales in the December quarter. We knew this would create a difficult compare for Q1’19, and this played out broadly in line with our expectations.
<br/>Second, we knew the strong US dollar would create foreign exchange headwinds and forecasted this would reduce our revenue growth by about 200 basis points as compared to the previous year. This also played out broadly in line with our expectations.
<br/>Third, we knew we had an unprecedented number of new products to ramp during the quarter and predicted that supply constraints would gate our sales of certain products during Q1. Again, this also played out broadly in line with our expectations. Sales of Apple Watch Series 4 and iPad Pro were constrained much or all of the quarter. AirPods and MacBook Air were also constrained.
<br/>Fourth, we expected economic weakness in some emerging markets. This turned out to have a significantly greater impact than we had projected. 
<br/>In addition, these and other factors resulted in fewer iPhone upgrades than we had anticipated. 
<br/>These last two points have led us to reduce our revenue guidance. I’d like to go a bit deeper on both. 
<br/><strong>Emerging Market Challenges</strong>
<br/>While we anticipated some challenges in key emerging markets, we did not foresee the magnitude of the economic deceleration, particularly in Greater China. In fact, most of our revenue shortfall to our guidance, and over 100 percent of our year-over-year worldwide revenue decline, occurred in Greater China across iPhone, Mac and iPad.
<br/>China’s economy began to slow in the second half of 2018. The government-reported GDP growth during the September quarter was the second lowest in the last 25 years. We believe the economic environment in China has been further impacted by rising trade tensions with the United States. As the climate of mounting uncertainty weighed on financial markets, the effects appeared to reach consumers as well, with traffic to our retail stores and our channel partners in China declining as the quarter progressed. And market data has shown that the contraction in Greater China’s smartphone market has been particularly sharp.
<br/>Despite these challenges, we believe that our business in China has a bright future. The iOS developer community in China is among the most innovative, creative and vibrant in the world. Our products enjoy a strong following among customers, with a very high level of engagement and satisfaction. Our results in China include a new record for Services revenue, and our installed base of devices grew over the last year. We are proud to participate in the Chinese marketplace.
<br/><strong>iPhone</strong>
<br/>Lower than anticipated iPhone revenue, primarily in Greater China, accounts for all of our revenue shortfall to our guidance and for much more than our entire year-over-year revenue decline. In fact, categories outside of iPhone (Services, Mac, iPad, Wearables/Home/Accessories) combined to grow almost 19 percent year-over-year. 
<br/>While Greater China and other emerging markets accounted for the vast majority of the year-over-year iPhone revenue decline, in some developed markets, iPhone upgrades also were not as strong as we thought they would be. While macroeconomic challenges in some markets were a key contributor to this trend, we believe there are other factors broadly impacting our iPhone performance, including consumers adapting to a world with fewer carrier subsidies, US dollar strength-related price increases, and some customers taking advantage of significantly reduced pricing for iPhone battery replacements. 
<br/><strong>Many Positive Results in the December Quarter</strong>
<br/>While it’s disappointing to revise our guidance, our performance in many areas showed remarkable strength in spite of these challenges. 
<br/>Our installed base of active devices hit a new all-time high—growing by more than 100 million units in 12 months. There are more Apple devices being used than ever before, and it’s a testament to the ongoing loyalty, satisfaction and engagement of our customers. 
<br/>Also, as I mentioned earlier, revenue outside of our iPhone business grew by almost 19 percent year-over-year, including all-time record revenue from Services, Wearables and Mac. Our non-iPhone businesses have less exposure to emerging markets, and the vast majority of Services revenue is related to the size of the installed base, not current period sales. 
<br/>Services generated over $10.8 billion in revenue during the quarter, growing to a new quarterly record in every geographic segment, and we are on track to achieve our goal of doubling the size of this business from 2016 to 2020.
<br/>Wearables grew by almost 50 percent year-over-year, as Apple Watch and AirPods were wildly popular among holiday shoppers; launches of MacBook Air and Mac mini powered the Mac to year-over-year revenue growth and the launch of the new iPad Pro drove iPad to year-over-year double-digit revenue growth. 
<br/>We also expect to set all-time revenue records in several developed countries, including the United States, Canada, Germany, Italy, Spain, the Netherlands and Korea. And, while we saw challenges in some emerging markets, others set records, including Mexico, Poland, Malaysia and Vietnam.
<br/>Finally, we also expect to report a new all-time record for Apple’s earnings per share.
<br/><strong>Looking Ahead</strong>
<br/>Our profitability and cash flow generation are strong, and we expect to exit the quarter with approximately $130 billion in net cash. As we have stated before, we plan to become net-cash neutral over time.
<br/>As we exit a challenging quarter, we are as confident as ever in the fundamental strength of our business. We manage Apple for the long term, and Apple has always used periods of adversity to re-examine our approach, to take advantage of our culture of flexibility, adaptability and creativity, and to emerge better as a result. 
<br/>Most importantly, we are confident and excited about our pipeline of future products and services. Apple innovates like no other company on earth, and we are not taking our foot off the gas.
<br/>We can’t change macroeconomic conditions, but we are undertaking and accelerating other initiatives to improve our results. One such initiative is making it simple to trade in a phone in our stores, finance the purchase over time, and get help transferring data from the current to the new phone. This is not only great for the environment, it is great for the customer, as their existing phone acts as a subsidy for their new phone, and it is great for developers, as it can help grow our installed base. 
<br/>This is one of a number of steps we are taking to respond. We can make these adjustments because Apple’s strength is in our resilience, the talent and creativity of our team, and the deeply held passion for the work we do every day.
<br/>Expectations are high for Apple because they should be. We are committed to exceeding those expectations every day.
<br/>That has always been the Apple way, and it always will be.
<br/>Tim
<br/>The information presented in this letter is preliminary and our actual results may differ. Apple plans to discuss final results during our first quarter conference call on Tuesday, January 29, 2019 at 2:00 p.m. PST / 5:00 p.m. EST.
<br/>This letter contains forward-looking statements, within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These forward-looking statements include without limitation those about Apple’s estimated revenue, gross margin, operating expenses, other income/(expense), tax rate, net cash, share count and plans for return of capital. These statements involve risks and uncertainties, and actual results may differ. Risks and uncertainties include without limitation: the effect of global and regional economic conditions on Apple’s business, including effects on purchasing decisions by consumers and businesses; the ability of Apple to compete in markets that are highly competitive and subject to rapid technological change; the ability of Apple to manage frequent introductions and transitions of products and services, including delivering to the marketplace, and stimulating customer demand for, new products, services and technological innovations on a timely basis; the effect that shifts in the mix of products and services and in the geographic, currency or channel mix, component cost increases, price competition, or the introduction of new products, including new products with higher cost structures, could have on Apple’s gross margin; the dependency of Apple on the performance of distributors of Apple’s products, including cellular network carriers and other resellers; the inventory and other asset risks associated with Apple’s need to order, or commit to order, product components in advance of customer orders; the continued availability on acceptable terms, or at all, of certain components, services and new technologies essential to Apple’s business, including components and technologies that may only be available from single or limited sources; the dependency of Apple on manufacturing and logistics services provided by third parties, many of which are located outside of the US and which may affect the quality, quantity or cost of products manufactured or services rendered to Apple; the effect of product and services design and manufacturing defects on Apple’s financial performance and reputation; the dependency of Apple on third-party intellectual property and digital content, which may not be available to Apple on commercially reasonable terms or at all; the dependency of Apple on support from third-party software developers to develop and maintain software applications and services for Apple’s products; the impact of unfavourable legal proceedings, such as a potential finding that Apple has infringed on the intellectual property rights of others; the impact of changes to laws and regulations that affect Apple’s activities, including Apple’s ability to offer products or services to customers in different regions; the ability of Apple to manage risks associated with its international activities, including complying with laws and regulations affecting Apple’s international operations; the ability of Apple to manage risks associated with Apple’s retail stores; the ability of Apple to manage risks associated with Apple’s investments in new business strategies and acquisitions; the impact on Apple’s business and reputation from information technology system failures, network disruptions or losses or unauthorised access to, or release of, confidential information; the ability of Apple to comply with laws and regulations regarding data protection; the continued service and availability of key executives and employees; political events, international trade disputes, war, terrorism, natural disasters, public health issues, and other business interruptions that could disrupt supply or delivery of, or demand for, Apple’s products; financial risks, including risks relating to currency fluctuations, credit risks and fluctuations in the market value of Apple’s investment portfolio; and changes in tax rates and exposure to additional tax liabilities. More information on these risks and other potential factors that could affect Apple’s financial results is included in Apple’s filings with the SEC, including in the “Risk Factors” and “Management’s Discussion and Analysis of Financial Condition and Results of Operations” sections of Apple’s most recently filed periodic reports on Form 10-K and Form 10-Q and subsequent filings. Apple assumes no obligation to update any forward-looking statements or information, which speak as of their respective dates.
<br/>Apple revolutionised personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>Investor Relations Contacts<br/>Nancy Paxton,Apple,paxton1@apple.com,+1 (408) 974-5420<br/>Matt Blake,Apple ,mattblake@apple.com,+1 (408) 974-7406<br/>© 2019 Apple Inc. All rights reserved. Apple and the Apple logo are trademarks of Apple Inc. Other company and product names may be trademarks of their respective owners.<br/>
]]></content></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-12-21T14:48:58.526Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[John Giannandrea named to Apple’s executive team]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/12/john-giannandrea-named-to-apples-executive-team/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[John Giannandrea named to Apple’s executive team<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced that John Giannandrea has been named to the company’s executive team as senior vice president of Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence Strategy. He joined Apple in April 2018.
<br/>Giannandrea oversees the strategy for AI and Machine Learning across all Apple products and services, as well as the development of Core ML and Siri technologies. His team's focus on advancing and tightly integrating machine learning into Apple products is delivering more personal, intelligent and natural interactions for customers while protecting user privacy. 
<br/>“John hit the ground running at Apple and we are thrilled to have him as part of our executive team,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “Machine learning and AI are important to Apple’s future as they are fundamentally changing the way people interact with technology, and already helping our customers live better lives. We’re fortunate to have John, a leader in the AI industry, driving our efforts in this critical area.” 
<br/>Giannandrea’s team is also helping to enhance the developer experience with tools including Core ML and Create ML, making it easier and faster to integrate machine learning into apps.
<br/>Apple revolutionized personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.<br>

<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-12-19T18:02:03.474Z]]></updated><category term="PHOTOS"/><title><![CDATA[Shot on iPhone XR and iPhone XS: Holiday cheer, winter landscapes and more]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/12/shot-on-iphone-xr-and-iphone-xs-holiday-cheer-winter-landscapes-and-more/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Shot on iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span> and iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span>: Holiday cheer, winter landscapes and more<br/>Photographers around the world are capturing stunning images this holiday season with iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">r</span>, iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">s</span> and iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">s</span> Max.
<br/>New camera features including Smart HDR bring better highlight and shadow detail across photos. iPhone’s Portrait mode adds a dramatic background blur, and the larger and deeper pixels improve low-light performance in photos.
<br/>For tips and techniques to help capture great photos and videos on iPhone, visit: <a href="https://www.apple.com/iphone/photography-how-to/" target="_blank">apple.com/iphone/photography-how-to/</a>.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/Shot-on-iPhone-holiday-Little-girl-with-string-lights-12192018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Photo courtesy of Erin Brooks." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-12-07T11:20:56.128Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple presents the best of 2018]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/12/apple-presents-the-best-of-2018/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple presents the best of 2018<br/>The Apps, Games, Music, Movies, TV Shows, Podcasts and More That Shaped Entertainment and Culture Around the World This Year<br/>As the year comes to a close there are so many unanswered questions: Who is Kiki, and does she love me? Should I start a podcast? Where is Donut County? Why didn’t Offred escape Gilead (again!)? Today, Apple reveals the Best of 2018, a global collection of top charts and selects from our editors across every category highlighting all of the amazing things to watch, read, listen to and play across apps, music, podcasts, books, TV and movies. It’s an invariable list of the who’s who and what’s what from the past year that is certain to help answer at least some of the most burning questions and make for fun conversation around any holiday dinner table.
<br/>The App Store<br>

<br/>This year, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1440852242?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1440852242&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Battle Royale-style games</a> like Fortnite and PUBG Mobile dominated global gaming culture with exciting, last-player-standing action, while innovative apps like Fabulous, Shine, 10% Happier and Headspace expanded the practice of wellness around the world to make <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438571562?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438571562&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">self-care more accessible</a> than ever before.
<br/><strong>Best Apps of the Year</strong>
<br/>App Trend of the Year -&nbsp;<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438571562?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438571562&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Self-care</a><br>
Game Trend of the Year -&nbsp;<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1440852242?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1440852242&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Battle Royale-style gaming</a><br>
iPhone App of the Year - <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438572731?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438572731&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Procreate Pocket</a><br>
iPhone Game of the Year - <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438572540?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438572540&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Donut County</a><br>
iPad App of the Year - <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438573233?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438573233&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Froggipedia</a><br>
iPad Game of the Year - <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438572836?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438572836&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Gorogoa</a><br>
Mac App of the Year - <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438573887?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438573887&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Pixelmator Pro</a><br>
Mac Game of the Year - <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438573677?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438573677&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">The Gardens Between</a><br>
Apple TV App of the Year - <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438570482?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438570482&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Sweat</a><br>
Apple TV Game of the Year - <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/story/id1438570482?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438570482&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Alto’s Odyssey</a><br>
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/story/id1441483812?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1441483812&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Favourite Watch Apps of the Year</a>
<br/><strong>Charts</strong>
<br/>iPhone users running iOS 11 and later will view iPhone charts below; iPad users running iOS 11 and later will view iPad charts. 
<br/><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/story/id1438574124?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438574124&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Top Apps Charts</a><br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/story/id1438573893?itsct=BESTOF_SC18_PT122_US_SI1438573893&amp;itscg=as10001" target="_blank">Top Games Charts</a>
<br/>Apple Music<br>

<br/>To close out an extraordinary year, Apple Music’s editors have awarded highest honours to the <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewMultiRoom?cc=us&amp;fcId=1441981146&amp;ls=1&amp;app=music&amp;at=1001ltS&amp;ct=rom_bestof2018&amp;itscg=30300&amp;itsct=rom_bestof2018" target="_blank">artists who truly represent the very best of 2018</a>. Drake owns the Artist of the Year category while country’s Kasey Musgraves scores Album of the Year for her dynamic <em>Golden Hour</em>. The fiery collaboration between Cardi B, J. Balvin and Bad Bunny made “I Like It” an easy choice for Song of the Year and Breakout Artist Juice WRLD has been giving everyone “Lucid Dreams” all year long. But these all-stars weren’t the only stars: Apple Music’s global year-end charts and editorial playlists are packed with the year’s biggest hits and favourites from all over the world.
<br/><strong>Best Music of the Year</strong>
<br/>Artist of the Year: Drake<br />
Breakout Artist of the Year: Juice WRLD<br />
Song of the Year: I Like It - Cardi B featuring Bad Bunny &amp; J. Balvin<br />
Album of the Year: Golden Hour - Kacey Musgraves
<br/><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewMultiRoom?fcId=1441993738&amp;ls=1&amp;app=music&amp;at=1001ltS&amp;ct=rom_bestof2018&amp;itscg=30300&amp;itsct=rom_bestof2018" target="_blank"><strong>Charts</strong></a>
<br/>Top 100 UK Songs<br>
Top 100 UK Albums
<br/>Apple Podcasts<br>

<br/>This year, investigative reporting underpinned the immersive storytelling of shows such as American Public Media’s <em>In the Dark</em>, <em>The New York Times’s</em> “Caliphate,” along with historical deep dives like Slate's<em> </em>“Slow Burn<em>.</em>”<em> </em>News and Politics grew as <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewFeature?id=1439382778&amp;mt=2&amp;ls=1" target="_blank">podcast</a> genres in 2018 with <em>The New York Times's</em> “The Daily” and Crooked Media’s “The Wilderness,” while celebrities and a healthy mix of independents topped this year’s new shows, including Dax Shepard’s “Armchair Expert<em>,</em>” “Oprah’s Master Class” and Parcast Network's “Conspiracy Theories” and “Unexplained Mysteries.”&nbsp;
<br/><strong>Best Podcasts of the Year</strong>
<br/>In The Dark<br />
Caliphate<br />
The Dream<br />
Everything is Alive<br />
Slow Burn<br />
Dr. Death<br />
Armchair Expert with Dax Shepard<br />
Bubble<br />
Bundyville<br />
A Very Fatal Murder<br />
Wolverine: The Long Night<br />
Serial<br />
The Daily<br />
This American Life<br />
99% Invisible
<br/><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewFeature?id=1439382778&amp;mt=2&amp;ls=1" target="_blank"><strong>Charts</strong></a>
<br/>Top 25 Most Downloaded Podcasts of the Year<br />
Top 25 Most Downloaded New Podcasts of the Year 
<br/>TV and Movies<br />

<br/>The <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewFeature?id=1439382778&amp;mt=2&amp;ls=1" target="_blank">movies and TV shows</a> of the year represent a rich mix of genres and topics ranging from indie, documentaries and animation to drama, horror and action. “Black Panther” and “Killing Eve” are the top picks of the year; they, along with other notable titles such as “Won’t You Be My Neighbor,” “Hereditary” and “Pose,” have been praised by critics and fans alike and fueled pop culture conversations and die-hard fandom around the world.
<br/><strong>Best Movies of 2018 on Apple TV and iTunes</strong>
<br/>Annihilation<br />
Black Panther<br />
Crazy Rich Asians <br />
Eighth Grade<br />
Green Book*<br />
Hereditary<br />
Incredibles 2 <br />
Minding the Gap<br />
A Star is Born*<br />
Won’t You Be My Neighbor<br />
*<em>available for pre-order</em>
<br/><strong>Best TV Shows of 2018 on Apple TV App and iTunes</strong>
<br/>The Americans<br />
Atlanta<br />
Barry<br />
The Expanse <br />
The Good Fight<br />
The Good Place<br />
The Handmaid’s Tale<br />
Killing Eve<br />
The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel<br />
Pose
<br/>Apple Books<br>

<br/>In 2018, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewFeature?id=1442158176&amp;mt=11&amp;ls=" target="_blank">Apple Books</a> launched as a brand new app, making it effortless for iPhone and iPad users to discover and enjoy books and audiobooks. This year Apple Books celebrates works from a diverse group of authors, including Tommy Orange's debut <em>There There</em>; Tayari Jones’s <em>American Marriage</em> that is both the Book and Audiobook of the Year; and Rachel Hollis's <em>Girl, Wash Your Face</em>. Politics dominated the U.S. charts this year with<em> Fire and Fury</em>, <em>Fear</em> and <em>A Higher Loyalty</em> all appearing in the top 10 best-selling nonfiction books. On the fiction front, readers remain rabid for books adapted for the screen, including Kevin Kwan’s <em>Crazy Rich Asians </em>and Gillian Flynn’s <em>Sharp Objects.</em>
<br/>Book of the Year: American Marriage<br />
Best Nonfiction: The Library Book <br />
Best Mystery: The Witch Elm<br />
Best Thriller: Light It Up<br />
Best Bio/Memoir: Educated <br />
Best Romance: Too Wilde to Wed<br />
Best Science Fiction/Fantasy: Spinning Silver <br />
Best Feel-Good Fiction: When Life Gives You Lululemons<br />
Best Literary Fiction: There There <br />
Best Young Reader Book: Harbor Me
<br/><strong>Best Audiobooks of the Year</strong>
<br/>Audiobook of the Year: American Marriage<br />
Best Nonfiction: 21 Lessons for the 21st Century <br />
Best Mystery: Something in the Water<br />
Best Thriller: Long Road to Mercy <br />
Best Bio/Memoir: Becoming <br />
Best Business Audiobook: Dare to Lead <br />
Best Health, Mind, Body: Girl, Wash Your Face<br />
Best Family Audiobook: Rebound <br />
Best Humor: Calypso <br />
Best Historical Fiction: The Great Alone
<br/><strong><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewFeature?id=1442158176&amp;mt=11&amp;ls=" target="_blank">2018 Apple Books Charts</a></strong>
<br/>Top 100 Books Fiction<br />
Top 100 Books Non-Fiction
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Apple Media Helpline ,media.emea@apple.com,+44 (0)20 8278 1440<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/watch/standard/Apple-presents-best-of-2018-Intro-12032018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/watch/standard/Apple-presents-best-of-2018-Apps-12032018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/watch/standard/Apple-presents-best-of-2018-Music-12032018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/watch/standard/Apple-presents-best-of-2018-Podcasts-12032018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Apple-presents-best-of-2018-TV-Shows-and-Movies-12032018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Apple-presents-best-of-2018-Books-and-Audiobooks-12032018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-12-04T02:23:48.835Z]]></updated><category term="FEATURE"/><title><![CDATA[The HIV-positive caregivers working to end AIDS in Africa]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/11/the-hiv-positive-caregivers-working-to-end-aids-in-africa/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[The HIV-positive caregivers working to end AIDS in Africa<br/>Dotty Nyambok is an HIV Counsellor at the Embakasi Health Centre in Nairobi, Kenya. She is halfway through her list of patients when two girls walk into her tent.
<br/>Helima, 18, is here because she suspects she’s contracted HIV from her boyfriend, and her friend Winny has come to support her.
<br/>Dotty begins a familiar ritual: She unwraps a sterilised needle, pricks Helima’s finger and drops blood onto a test strip. Then she sets the timer. 15:00, 14:59, 14:58…
<br/>While they wait, Dotty asks Helima what she thinks will happen if she tests positive. With grim confidence, she answers, she will die.
<br/>That’s when Dotty shares something of herself. It’s information she reveals when she senses someone is in desperate need of kindness and hope.
<br/>“I’m HIV-positive,” Dotty says. “So when you have HIV you will continue living, because you will take your medication.”
<br/>The girls exchange surprised, shy smiles in the tent at Embakasi, a facility whose HIV treatment services have been supported by Apple’s (RED) partnership since 2012.
<br/>Since its founding by Bono and Bobby Shriver, (RED) has raised more than $600 million to support the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria, $200 million of which has come from its partnership with Apple, the organisation’s largest corporate donor.
<br/>Last year, Kenya had 53,000 new cases of HIV. Young women are infected at twice the rate as young men. As high as these numbers seem, they’re a vast improvement from years ago.
<br/>In 2000, a staggering 9.3 percent of all adults in Kenya were HIV-positive. At the same time, because the drugs were in short supply, World Health Organization guidelines stipulated that lifesaving antiretrovirals (ARVs) should only be administered once a patient’s CD4 count, which measures immune system health, fell below a very low mark. It meant patients had to be extremely sick to access ARVs, and for many, that was too late.
<br/>5:27, 5:26, 5:25…
<br/>That grim landscape was recent history when Dotty discovered she was pregnant in 2007, at age 19. During a prenatal visit, a clinician told Dotty she was HIV-positive, and pointed her to a treatment clinic two hours away. There was no counselling, no compassion, and no follow-up.
<br/>The experience left her traumatised and in denial — she didn’t tell anyone about her status and didn’t seek treatment.
<br/>Dotty’s son died in her arms at just six weeks old. He was buried in a cooking oil box — the smallest they could find.
<br/>A few months later, Dotty went to the Embakasi Health Centre.
<br/>It’s one of thousands of facilities in Kenya and seven other countries in Sub-Saharan Africa that began receiving support from the Global Fund in 2002.
<br/>The Global Fund has helped to radically change access to HIV treatment, and provides 17.5 million people with ARVs — now available from the moment they test positive. As a result, Kenya has seen a 52 percent drop in new HIV infections since 2000. As of last year, just 4.8 percent of all adults were HIV-positive.
<br/>“I decided to do counselling because I really don’t want what happened to me to repeat itself.”
<br/>In 2009, Embakasi opened a special Comprehensive Care Clinic (CCC) for HIV patients that distributes ARVs, made possible largely from Global Fund grants.
<br/>“The Global Fund and (RED) have made a huge impact in the lives of HIV-positive patients,” says Robina Anene Muli, who runs the Embakasi Health Centre. “Especially when it comes to testing kits, ARVs and other drugs — they provide 80 percent of our supplies and funding.”
<br/>3:13, 3:12, 3:11…
<br/>During her first year at Embakasi, Dotty was introduced to the Mentor Mothers, a group of peer educators who are HIV-positive and have given birth to HIV-negative babies after taking ARVs. The group was created as part of the CCC expansion, with Global Fund grants.
<br/>After a few months of treatment, Dotty found out she was pregnant again.
<br/>On November 7th, 2009, Dotty gave birth to a healthy baby boy. “Now I had a reason to live,” she says. “Because of Morgan. He saved my life.”
<br/>When Morgan was six months old, Dotty applied to be a Mentor Mother at Embakasi.
<br/>“I decided to do counselling because I really don’t want what happened to me to repeat itself,” says Dotty. “My purpose is to touch a heart — and if I diagnose someone I feel like we are then attached.”
<br/>In many facilities, HIV-positive peer educators like Dotty are changing the way people live with HIV.
<br/>“Peer educators are a vital piece of the most effective HIV treatment programs,” says Luisa Engel, Chief Impact Officer at (RED). “Their work ensures lifesaving information reaches the people who need it most, and they act as a powerful force against stigma.”
<br/>Three years ago, Dotty started a new role at Embakasi, as an HIV Testing Counsellor. Sometimes she takes an HIV test in front of her patients, to prove she has the virus and to show them that a full and vibrant life is possible.
<br/>“I would like to see a different perception about HIV,” says Dotty. “And that’s what I hope to do when I disclose my status.”
<br/>:03, :02, :01…
<br/>Back in Dotty’s tent, Helima’s results are ready. She places the test strip in between examples of what a positive and negative result look like.
<br/>“Tell me what you see and what it means,” says Dotty.
<br/>“Negative,” says Helima. In an instant, the tension dissolves. After a chat about how to protect themselves, Dotty sends the girls off with warm goodbyes.
<br/>On Dotty’s walk home that night, she picks up some meat to cook for dinner on the hotplate in the one-room apartment she and Morgan, now nine years old, share.
<br/>After dinner, at 7:58 p.m., an alarm on Dotty’s phone sounds. It signals the start of a ritual they have repeated every night for the last two years — ever since Morgan was old enough to understand his mom’s illness.
<br/>Morgan walks over to a small dresser, pulls out a bottle of pills and carefully taps one out. He hands the ARV to his mother, who swallows it with water.
<br/>These are the frontlines of the war against AIDS in Africa. And this is how it is won, one expression of love, one act of kindness, at a time.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/red-and-global-fund_clinic-overview_11292018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Dotty Nyambok provides HIV testing and treatment at the Embakasi Health Centre in Nairobi, Kenya." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/red-and-global-fund_nairobi-testing_11292018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Dotty counsels Helima, who suspects she contracted HIV from her boyfriend. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/red-and-global-fund_nairobi-blood-testing_11292018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A finger prick is used for a rapid HIV test, which provides results in 15 minutes." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/red-and-global-fund_nairobi-children_11292018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The Embakasi Health Centre supports thousands of patients, including those seeking general medical treatment not related to HIV." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/red-and-global-health-center-sign_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The Embakasi Health Centre is one of many facilities in Kenya that receives support from the Global Fund." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/RED-and-Global_Fund_HIV_testing-facts_11292018.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/RED-and-Global-Fund_Nairobi-Dotty-Morgan_11292018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Dotty credits her son Morgan with saving her life and giving her hope for the future." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/red-and-global-fund_clinic-education_11292018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Dotty has been an HIV Testing Counsellor at Embakasi for three years." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/red-and-global-fund_test-results_11292018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Dotty counsels patients on how to have a full life should they receive an HIV-positive diagnosis." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/partnerships/red-and-global-fund_medication_11292018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Dotty’s son Morgan now helps her take her HIV medication before bed every night." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-11-29T17:32:48.555Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple launches app development program to support women entrepreneurs]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/11/apple-launches-app-development-program-to-support-women-entrepreneurs/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple launches app development program to support women entrepreneurs<br/>New Entrepreneur Camp Offers Immersive Technology Lab and More for Female App Developers who are Founders and Entrepreneurs<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced the launch of the all-new Entrepreneur Camp, a first-of-its-kind initiative designed to create new opportunities for app-driven businesses owned or led by women through an intensive technology lab, specialised support and ongoing mentoring.
<br/>To be eligible for the program, applying app-driven businesses must be female-founded, co-founded or led and have at least one woman on the development team — as well as a working app or prototype and desire to leverage Apple technologies to benefit their mission. The program’s pilot session, beginning in January 2019, is now <a href="https://developer.apple.com/entrepreneur-camp/" target="_blank">accepting applications</a>. 
<br/>“Apple is committed to helping more women assume leadership roles across the tech sector and beyond,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “We’re proud to help cultivate female leadership in the app development community with the new Apple Entrepreneur Camp, and we’re inspired both by the incredible work that’s already happening, and what’s sure to come.”&nbsp;
<br/>“This is a program that matters,” said Gina Bianchini, investor and founder and CEO of Mighty Networks. “The new Entrepreneur Camp says Apple wants to invest its expertise in a different, richer, more diverse range of app developers and product experts in a meaningful way, and that is a big deal for the industry.”
<br/>Entrepreneur Camp will hold sessions on a quarterly basis, with a cohort of 20 app companies accepted for each round. The pilot session will include 10 companies.
<br/>Once accepted, each company will have the opportunity to send three attendees to Cupertino, California for a two-week immersive program at Apple’s campus, including one-on-one code-level assistance with Apple engineers, sessions on design, technology and App Store marketing, as well as ongoing guidance and support from an Apple Developer representative. Each participating company will also receive two tickets to the following year's WWDC.
<br/>Female entrepreneurs continue to face challenges obtaining funding, training and support in the VC landscape — receiving $1.9 billion in funding in 2017 compared to $83.1 billion for men. Despite such obstacles, women-owned businesses are growing more than two times faster than the US national average, with women-led tech startups delivering a 35 percent higher return on investment than tech startups led by men. 
<br/>For more information on Apple Entrepreneur Camp or to apply, visit <a href="https://developer.apple.com/entrepreneur-camp/" target="_blank">developer.apple.com/entrepeneur-camp</a>. 
<br/>Apple revolutionised personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/passions/business/Apple-announces-entrepreneur-camp-program-to-empower-women-11262018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple’s new program aims to help women-led businesses leverage technology to make a meaningful impact for their customers." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/passions/business/Apple-announces-entrepreneur-camp-program-to-empower-women-on-computer-11262018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="As part of the program, cohorts will travel to Apple’s campus in Cupertino for two weeks of hands-on training and programming." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/passions/business/Apple-announces-entrepreneur-camp-program-to-empower-women-presentation-11262018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple Entrepreneur Camp sessions will be held once a quarter, with each cohort comprising participants from 20 companies." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-11-26T21:20:47.430Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple brings coding education to more students for Computer Science Education Week]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/11/apple-brings-coding-education-to-more-students-for-computer-science-education-week/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple brings coding education to more students for Computer Science Education Week<br/>Free Hour of Code Sessions Come to all Apple Store Locations Next Week<br/>Apple today unveiled new resources designed to bring coding education through the Everyone Can Code program to even more students around the world. Starting today, customers can register for thousands of free <a href="https://www.apple.com/today/collection/hourofcode/" target="_blank">Hour of Code</a> sessions, available at all Apple Store locations around the world from December 1 to 14.
<br/>The company also introduced Swift Coding Club materials to help teach coding outside of the classroom with Swift, Apple’s easy-to-learn programming language used by professional developers to create world-class apps. And to help prepare and develop students for the workforce, the company unveiled a new App Development with Swift certification.
<br/>Today at Apple
<br/>For the sixth year, Apple will host Hour of Code daily coding sessions through Today at Apple from December 1 to 14. The sessions will provide opportunities for people at a variety of skill levels to learn coding. Kids Hour sessions will help aspiring coders aged six to 12 explore coding with robots, while those aged 12 and above can attend sessions using Swift Playgrounds and iPad to learn coding concepts.
<br/>More Ways to Introduce Students to Coding
<br/>To celebrate Computer Science Education Week, Apple created a new&nbsp;<a href="https://apple.co/HOCFacilitatorGuide" target="_blank">Hour of Code Facilitator Guide</a>&nbsp;to help educators host sessions in their classroom using Swift Playgrounds and other iPad apps. Swift Playgrounds is available as a free download in the App Store in 15 languages, including English, German, French, Spanish, Italian, Chinese and Japanese.
<br/>To teach coding outside of the classroom, a new <a href="https://apple.co/SwiftCodingClubKit" target="_blank">Swift Coding Club kit</a> gives teachers, students and club mentors the tools they need to start their own coding clubs. The new kit gives students aged 8 and up the ability to collaborate, prototype apps and explore how coding can make a difference in their communities using fun activities from Swift Playgrounds and App Development with Swift.
<br/>Preparing Students for the Workforce
<br/>The App Development with Swift curriculum gives high school and college students the critical skills they need to qualify for high-demand and high-skill jobs.
<br/>Students can also earn a certification that recognises their knowledge of Swift, app developer tools and core components of apps. The App Development with Swift Level 1 certification exams are offered through Certiport Authorised Testing Centres worldwide.
<br/>Apple and Education
<br/>In 2016, Apple launched Everyone Can Code, a comprehensive program and curriculum to help students from kindergarten to university and beyond learn coding to solve problems and prepare them for the workforce. With teacher guides and lessons, students learn the basics on iPad with Swift Playgrounds, which uses real code to solve puzzles and control characters with just a tap. And App Development with Swift helps aspiring app developers build their first iOS apps. Today more than 5,000 schools, universities and technical colleges worldwide are using Everyone Can Code curriculum.
<br/>Apple’s Everyone Can Code joins <a href="https://www.apple.com/education/everyone-can-create/" target="_blank">Everyone Can Create</a> as one-of-a-kind programs for teachers that help engage students in learning while building new skills in fun and meaningful ways. Designed to help unleash kids’ creativity, Everyone Can Create teaches students to develop and communicate ideas through drawing, music, video and photos on iPad.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/passions/education/computer-science-education-week_children-instore-education_11262018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="All Apple Stores will host free Hour of Code sessions from December 1 to 14." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/passions/education/computer-science-education-week_ipads_11262018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="New resources help students learn to code both in and outside of the classroom." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/passions/education/computer-science-education-week_instore-swift-playground_11262018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Free Today at Apple sessions give people at all skill levels the opportunity to learn to code." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/passions/education/computer-science-education-week_coding-sphero_11262018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A new Swift Coding Club kit inspires students to learn to code through interactive activities." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/passions/education/computer-science-education-week_workforce_11262018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="New certification helps students build skills for future careers." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-11-19T12:29:39.431Z]]></updated><category term="PHOTOS"/><title><![CDATA[Apple Champs-Élysées now open in Paris]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/11/apple-champs-elysees-now-open-in-paris/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple Champs-Élysées now open in Paris<br/>Apple Champs-Élysées opened this afternoon in Paris, welcoming thousands of customers along the world-famous shopping street.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/live-action/new-store-opening/apple-champs-elysees_team-celebration_11182018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Employees celebrate the grand opening with the first customers at Apple Champs-Élysées." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/live-action/new-store-opening/apple-champs-elysees_exterior_11182018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Thousands of customers joined Apple to celebrate the opening, queuing along Champs-Élysées." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/live-action/new-store-opening/apple-champs-elysees_renewable-energy_11182018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Powered by 100 percent renewable energy, Apple Champs-Élysées features several environmental design elements." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/live-action/new-store-opening/apple-champs-elysees_apple-watch_11182018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="More than 200 of Apple Champs-Élysées’s highly-trained employees join the team from other stores in Paris." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/live-action/new-store-opening/apple-champs-elysees_today-at-apple_11182018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="In the Forum, Apple Champs-Élysées will host daily Today at Apple sessions, focused on photography, music, coding, design and more." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/live-action/new-store-opening/apple-champs-elysees_iphone-xr_11182018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Customers try out the new iPhone XR." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/live-action/new-store-opening/apple-champs-elysees_apple-team_11182018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The team at Apple Champs-Élysées represents over 15 nationalities and speaks 17 languages." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/live-action/new-store-opening/apple-champs-elysees_apple-visitor-ipad_11182018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A young visitor gets hands-on with iPad during a Today at Apple session at Apple Champs-Élysées." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-11-16T17:21:49.458Z]]></updated><category term="PHOTOS"/><title><![CDATA[Shot on iPhone XR: Users share portraits, landscapes and more  ]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/11/shot-on-iphone-xr-users-share-portraits-landscapes-and-more/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Shot on iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span>: Users share portraits, landscapes and more  <br/>Photographers around the world are capturing stunning images with iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span>, the newest member of the iPhone family. iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span> features an Apple-designed, state-of-the-art camera system that enables Portrait mode from a single lens, offering a sophisticated bokeh effect. Portraits look great on the wide-angle lens, even in lower lighting conditions.<br/>iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span>’s edge-to-edge 6.1-inch Liquid Retina display makes for a great viewfinder, and Smart HDR brings better highlight and shadow detail across photos. With the longest battery life in an iPhone ever, iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span> will be ready to snap that perfect shot.<br/>For tips and techniques to help capture great photos and videos on iPhone, visit <a href="https://www.apple.com/iphone/photography-how-to/" target="_blank">apple.com/iphone/photography-how-to</a>.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/shot-on-iphonexr_austin-mann_portrait_woman_with_hat_11142018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Photo courtesy of Austin Mann." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-11-15T21:17:47.902Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Final Cut Pro X introduces third-party workflow extensions ]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/lu/newsroom/2018/11/final-cut-pro-x-introduces-third-party-workflow-extensions/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Final Cut Pro X introduces third-party workflow extensions<br/>Update Brings Extensions from Frame.io, Shutterstock and CatDV, Plus Other Features Including Batch Sharing, Video Noise Reduction and Comparison Viewer<br/>The latest update to Final Cut Pro X, available today on the Mac App Store, introduces workflow extensions that enable professional video editors to use third-party apps and services directly within the editing interface.
<br/>Workflow extensions match the look of Final Cut Pro and integrate tightly into the app, allowing editors to drag media into Final Cut Pro libraries, sync playback between extensions and timeline, add clip markers and more. These extensions make it easy to use popular tools that enhance post-production including review and approval with Frame.io, stock footage browsing and purchasing with Shutterstock and media asset management with CatDV. Workflow extensions can be downloaded free from the Mac App Store starting today. Additional third-party extensions for Final Cut Pro will be available on an ongoing basis.
<br/>The new version of Final Cut Pro also includes a number of features that are highly requested from pro video editors. Batch sharing allows a user to export multiple clips or projects in one step and is especially useful when transcoding dailies on set for quick turnaround or delivering multiple versions of a project. A new Comparison Viewer window lets editors view reference images while colour grading to ensure a consistent look across their project.
<br/>A new floating timecode window makes it easy for video editors and others in the editing room to follow along by displaying colour-coded clip names, roles, project timecode and source timecode in a customisable, resizable display. High-quality video noise reduction minimises artefacts in low light or archival footage. Editors can now create and deliver closed captions in SRT format or choose to burn them into their video for compatibility with a wide range of video websites. And improved marquee selection makes it quick to select individual clips or the entire secondary storyline which saves valuable time for common edit operations.
<br/>Motion, the powerful motion graphics companion to Final Cut Pro, also gets an update today that adds a comprehensive set of colour grading tools including colour wheels, colour curves, hue/saturation curves and custom LUTs. These tools match the professional colour correction features found in Final Cut Pro and can now be used in Motion to fine-tune the look of titles and motion graphics. New filters in Motion include a customisable comic effect that instantly turns any image or video into colour or monochrome comic book illustration. And the new tiny planet filter lets motion graphics artists transform 360-degree video into beautiful spherical animations that can be keyframed to change over time.
<br/>Compressor, the advanced encoding companion to Final Cut Pro, moves to a new 64-bit engine that takes advantage of all the memory in a user’s Mac for improved performance when encoding high resolution, high frame rate video. Compressor maintains support for 32-bit codecs, so editors can continue to work with key legacy formats. And the app now supports SRT closed captions, which is an important format for delivering captioned video to the web and international markets.
<br/><strong>Pricing and Availability</strong>
<br/>Final Cut Pro 10.4.4, Motion 5.4.2 and Compressor 4.4.2 will be available on the Mac App Store as free updates for existing users. New users can purchase the apps $<strong>299.99</strong>,<strong> $48.99</strong> and <strong>$48.99,</strong> respectively. Education customers can purchase the Pro Apps Bundle for Education for <strong>$199.99</strong>, which includes all three pro video apps plus Logic Pro X and MainStage. For more information, visit <a href="https://www.apple.com/final-cut-pro/" target="_blank">apple.com/final-cut-pro</a>.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Juriaan Bosman,Apple,media.emea@apple.com,+44 (0)20 8278 1440<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.emea@apple.com<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Final-Cut-Pro-X-woman-at-work-station-11152018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The latest update to Final Cut Pro X introduces third-party workflow extensions and a host of new highly requested features for professional video creators. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Final-Cut-Pro-X-workflow-extensions-frameio-11152018_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Workflow extensions make it possible to use popular tools and services from developers like Frame.io, Shutterstock and CatDV from right within the Final Cut Pro interface." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Final-Cut-Pro-X-workflow-extensions-shutterstock-11152018_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Workflow extensions make it possible to use popular tools and services from developers like Frame.io, Shutterstock and CatDV from right within the Final Cut Pro interface. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Final-Cut-Pro-X-workflow-extensions-CatDV-11152018_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Workflow extensions make it possible to use popular tools and services from developers like Frame.io, Shutterstock and CatDV from right within the Final Cut Pro interface. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Final-Cut-Pro-X-screen-1-11152018_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A new Comparison Viewer makes it easy to view reference images while users are colour grading clips in the Final Cut Pro timeline." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Final-Cut-Pro-X-timecode-11152018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A floating timecode window makes collaborating easier by displaying project and source timecode in one or more floating, customisable timecode windows." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/videos/final-cut-pro-x-tiny-planet/Tiny-Planet-cc-us-_848x480.mp4" rel="enclosure" title="Final Cut Pro X 360 video" type="video/mp4"/></entry></feed>