<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/]]></id><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-18T13:58:37.056Z]]></updated><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-18T13:58:37.056Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple and Dream Corps build career opportunities for Oakland coders]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/02/apple-and-dream-corps-build-career-opportunities-for-oakland-coders/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple and Dream Corps build career opportunities for Oakland coders<br/>As part of its Community Education Initiative, Apple will partner with Oakland-based non-profit organization Dream Corps to bring educational and workforce development opportunities to young adults with a goal of career placement in the tech sector.
<br/>The partnership will build on the success of Dream Corps’ #YesWeCode Initiative, which aims “to help 100,000 young women and men from underrepresented backgrounds find success in the tech sector.” #YesWeCode has graduated four coding cohorts and has over a 60 percent job placement rate.
<br/>“We are thrilled about launching this new initiative in Oakland,” said Lisa Jackson, Apple’s vice president of Environment, Policy and Social Initiatives. “Our hope is that by bringing expertise, stakeholders and resources together, we’ll be able to magnify the already impressive impact that Dream Corps is having in the Bay Area and across the nation and help a new generation of young people realize their potential.”
<br/>“This partnership with Apple will help unlock the untapped genius and talent within those communities, which will allow a new generation to achieve their dreams.”
<br/>Apple will provide technology as well as professional support, curriculum guidance and advocacy to individuals in middle and high school, college and beyond. Participants will be exposed to a number of skills and tools to enhance career prospects, with an emphasis on coding with Swift.&nbsp;
<br/>Vien Truong is the CEO of Dream Corps. She’s the youngest of 11 children, born to an immigrant couple who migrated from Vietnam in the 1970s. She and her family have called Oakland home for decades. She joined Dream Corps in 2015 with the goal of expanding opportunities to young people in Oakland and beyond.
<br/>“I see Dream Corps as a peace corps for the American Dream,” said Truong. “It’s about making sure that we can help support people who lived or grew up in communities like mine. And this partnership with Apple will help unlock the untapped genius and talent within those communities, which will allow a new generation to achieve their dreams.”
<br/>Apple and Dream Corps’ coding programming is set to launch later this year in the Bay Area. Dream Corps is working with the Mayor's Office and the City of Oakland to identify and assess potential locations for a dedicated space to support this program and other related workforce development and social entrepreneurship efforts.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Rachel Wolf Tulley,Apple, rachel_tulley@apple.com , (408) 974-0078<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-and-Dream-Corps-build-career-opportunities-for-Oakland-coders_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Vien Truong, Dream Corps CEO, will work with Apple to bring coding and workforce development programs to local youth." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-and-Dream-Corps-build-career-opportunities-members-collaborate-in-headquarters-02182019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Members of Dream Corps collaborate in the non-profit’s Oakland headquarters. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-and-Dream-Corps-build-career-opportunities-Vien-Truong-02182019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Vien Truong has deep ties to the city of Oakland, where she lives with her family. " type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-18T13:56:10.626Z]]></updated><category term="FEATURE"/><title><![CDATA[A career in tech, built with coding and determination]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/02/a-career-in-tech-built-with-coding-and-determination/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[A career in tech, built with coding and determination<br/>Coming from a military family, Gerald Ingraham knew he would join the Marines. But after completing his service, and before he learned to code, the Californian says he was “a ship without a rudder and a sail.”
<br/>The father of two spent 15 years alternating between administration and construction jobs that left him seeking greater fulfillment and financial stability. That need compounded when his eldest son was diagnosed with brain cancer and Ingraham and his wife struggled to keep pace with a growing pile of medical bills.
<br/>Searching for options, Ingraham found a video online called “Are you too old to be a programmer?” He decided that he wasn’t and would teach himself how to code. 
<br/>“The main thing that the Marine Corps teaches you is never to quit,” said Ingraham. “So I didn’t quit.” But after months of struggling with online tutorials, he knew he needed help. And that’s when he discovered the Dream Corps #YesWeCode initiative.
<br/>Dream Corps was founded in 2015, with a mission to transform the criminal justice system while opening doors of opportunity for those who need it most. One of its main programs is #YesWeCode, which aims “to help 100,000 young women and men from underrepresented backgrounds find success in the tech sector,” and was founded with support from the late musician Prince. The program has graduated four cohorts of approximately 25 people — and 60 percent have gone on to start new jobs in tech.&nbsp;
<br/>“I’m finally doing something I chose, not something I just fell into because that was the only skill I had.”
<br/>Now, <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/02/apple-and-dream-corps-build-career-opportunities-for-oakland-coders/" target="_blank">Apple and Dream Corps are partnering</a> to take that success even further as part of Apple’s Community Education Initiative. Building on #YesWeCode’s established track record, the program will expand educational and workforce development opportunities to young adults in Oakland and eventually nationally, with a focus on coding with Swift.&nbsp;These efforts are designed to reach learners in middle and high school, college and beyond, opening doors to careers in the tech sector. Apple will provide technology as well as professional support, curriculum guidance and advocacy.
<br/>In 2017, Gerald Ingraham completed the #YesWeCode program while also working full-time. His dedication paid off a year later, when he landed a job as a software developer at a video game company.
<br/>“I’m finally doing something I chose,” said Ingraham, “not something I just fell into because that was the only skill I had. I feel better about myself — and my oldest son told me how I’ve inspired him.” 
<br/>That’s the same son Ingraham nurtured back to health after surviving brain cancer. He’s now in college studying business — inspired by a father who never quit, and proud to follow in his footsteps. 
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Rachel Wolf Tulley,Apple, rachel_tulley@apple.com , (408) 974-0078<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-a-career-in-tech-Gerald-Ingraham-02182019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Gerald Ingraham was looking for a more fulfilling career before he found YesWeCode. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-a-career-in-tech-Gerald-Ingraham-former-Marine-02182019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The former Marine was determined to learn new skills, even if it meant he had to teach himself." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-a-career-in-tech-Gerald-Ingraham-and-his-wife-02182019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Gerald Ingraham and his wife struggled to pay the bills before he found a job coding. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-a-career-in-tech-Gerald-Ingraham-and-son-02182019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Gerald Ingraham and his oldest son, who survived brain cancer." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-13T21:56:53.855Z]]></updated><category term="FEATURE"/><title><![CDATA[Behind the Mac creator celebrates his literary icon]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/02/behind-the-mac-creator-celebrates-his-literary-icon/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Behind the Mac creator celebrates his literary icon<br/>Barry Jenkins on James Baldwin, Filming Black Skin and Filmmaking in the iPhone Era<br/>Oscar-winning director Barry Jenkins says he “stumbled into filmmaking,” attending Florida State University for some years before discovering its film school. “I went to film school right at the turn between old school cinema and new school cinema,” Jenkins says, “so we actually learned to edit films on these things called flat beds … you have to actually physically cut the film and tape it back together. So, doing that for a full year and then transitioning to what they call non-linear editing, it was shocking.
<br/>“But I took the lessons with me,” he continues. “Only make the cuts you absolutely have to make.”
<br/>In last year’s Behind the Mac campaign that celebrates creators using Mac in their work, Jenkins is seen holding his MacBook Pro while standing under an umbrella in the rain. The director was exporting the final cut of his 2017 Academy Award-winning feature film, “Moonlight.”
<br/>Trained in traditional and modern filmmaking, Jenkins blends his craft with digital equipment like his ARRI Alexa camera, MacBook Pro and even his new iPad Pro. “These Arri cameras and the Apple platform are the two things that have helped me become the maker that I am,” Jenkins says.
<br/>His latest film, adapted from James Baldwin’s “If Beale Street Could Talk,” is a cautionary tale about black life in America in the 1970s, spotlighting the hardships a young couple face navigating a changing world around them. The novel was published in 1974, six years after Martin Luther King Jr.’s assassination in 1968, and a decade after the passage of the 1964 Civil Rights Act.
<br/>Baldwin’s literary tone is critical and unapologetic about his analysis of the state of the world around him. He crafts a delicate balance between the beauty and the brutality of America.
<br/>In Jenkins’s adaptation, that balance is achieved through portraits of moments shared between Tish (played by KiKi Layne) and Fonny (Stephan James), from the streets of Harlem to the West Village, to the bulletproof glass at the Manhattan Detention Complex — or the Tombs.
<br/>“My job in making this film, from the craft standpoint, from the aesthetic standpoint, was about trying to translate interiority into sounds and images, and to do so with the words of James Baldwin.”
<br/>To translate Baldwin’s words into moving pictures, Tish narrates the events that led to her and Fonny’s current status: in love, expecting and fighting for Fonny’s freedom after his wrongful arrest.
<br/>“The movie is composed of memory streams and nightmares and so how does 19-year-old Tish, how does <em>she</em> view Harlem?” Jenkins continues. “How does <em>she</em> want to remember it? And once we hit on that, that’s when the whole world opened up for us.”
<br/>“If Beale Street Could Talk” is the first English-language fiction adaptation of Baldwin, a feat with its own set of unique challenges.
<br/>“Literature is a very interior medium, it’s all about the interior voice,” Jenkins says. “And cinema, it’s about externally acting out in a certain way. You know, sounds and images. You’re not necessarily allowed to be inside the character, and James Baldwin, the power of his writing is all about the interior voice. So my job in making this film, from the craft standpoint, from the aesthetic standpoint, was about trying to translate interiority into sounds and images, and to do so with the words of James Baldwin.”
<br/>Shot on an ARRI Alexa 65, “Beale Street” gives audiences a close, intimate look at black life. Jenkins is grateful for the ability to capture the intimacies of black family and love, dreamed up by his literary icon, in such a large format.
<br/>“The history of [cinema] is all tied to 35 mm emulsion,” Jenkins explains. “These cameras now are programmable computer chips so you can write the algorithms to dictate how they behave, how they perceive light. In the past, you were limited in some ways by how certain film stocks were created and what their dynamic range was. Now, whenever we set up to make a film, we can program the computer … from scratch. So right away, we’re building these cameras to prioritize darker colors, by which I mean darker skin tones. It’s very freeing.”
<br/>Beyond the new cameras, filmmaking still requires a bit of magic. Enter the editor.
<br/>Joi McMillon is a longtime Jenkins collaborator. One of the two Oscar-nominated editors on “Moonlight,” she “breathes” Avid on the Mac Pro. McMillon worked with Jenkins and cinematographer James Laxton to bring the film to life.
<br/>In one scene, Fonny and Daniel (Brian Tyree Henry) spend hours in Fonny’s apartment catching up, moving from small talk to something troubling for Daniel.
<br/>“It’s kind of like a scene within a scene, and they change up the lighting and the angle and so as an audience member, you’re not exhausted by being somewhere for that long,” McMillon explains. “There’s now new information in each section of that part of the film.”
<br/>Jenkins wanted the audience to feel the energy being transferred between Fonny and Daniel. A camera slides slowly between them, a progression deeper and deeper into Daniel’s mind and Fonny’s reaction.
<br/>“There’s such warmth on Fonny and Daniel’s skin and yet what they’re talking about is so dark and scary and I just love the juxtaposition of that,” McMillon says. “The way it’s shot makes you feel like you’re sitting at the table with them.”
<br/>That immersion is now a Jenkins staple. Audiences sat at a similar table in a diner in “Moonlight,” and even floated in the ocean with those characters.
<br/>Today Jenkins, McMillon and the “Beale Street” family are once again on the awards circuit. The film is nominated for three Oscars: Best Supporting Actress (Regina King), Best Original Music Score (Nicholas Britell) and Best Adapted Screenplay (Jenkins).
<br/>“Even the old school cats that are embracing these new tools … they get down and dirty digitally.”
<br/>Up next: An Amazon series based on Colson Whitehead’s “The Underground Railroad.” Jenkins jokes this will round out his artistic bucket list: “Make a movie about where I was from, and that became ‘Moonlight.’ I also wanted to adapt my favorite author, and that’s ‘Beale Street.’ And the last was I wanted to make something about the condition of American slavery. And that’s ‘The Underground Railroad.’”
<br/>As Jenkins ticks off his list, he acknowledges a new class of filmmakers he says he’s sure will lap him soon. “Even the old school cats that are embracing these new tools … they get down and dirty digitally,” Jenkins says. “Steven Soderbergh has been working almost exclusively off the iPhone for the last few years.” (Soderbergh’s latest film, “High Flying Bird,” was shot entirely on an iPhone 8 and premiered on Netflix last month.)
<br/>“You can kind of make any damn thing right now, whether with your phone or with a DSLR,” he says. “The world is a young filmmaker’s oyster.”
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Jennie Orphanopoulos,Apple, jennieo@apple.com,(408) 221-6621<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-02132019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Director Barry Jenkins discusses “If Beale Street Could Talk,” his third feature film, and the potential of today’s young filmmakers. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-on-set-02132019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Barry Jenkins on set with actors Dave Franco, Stephan James and KiKi Layne. Photo courtesy of Tatum Mangus / Annapurna Pictures." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-If-Beale-Street-Could-Talk-02132019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="“If Beale Street Could Talk” is the first English-language adaptation of James Baldwin, a prominent author on race relations in the US during the Civil Rights Era. Photo courtesy of Tatum Mangus / Annapurna Pictures." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-holding-MacBook-Pro-02132019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Filmmaker Barry Jenkins, featured in Apple’s Behind the Mac ad, exports the final cut of his Academy Award-winning film, “Moonlight.”" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-behind-the-Mac-creator-Barry-Jenkins-sence-from-If-Beale-Street-Could-Talk-02132019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="From left: Fonny played by Stephan James, Tish KiKi Layne and Daniel Brian Tyree Henry in Fonny’s apartment, moments before Daniel opens up about his incarceration in “If Beale Street Could Talk.” Photo courtesy of Tatum Mangus / Annapurna Pictures." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-11T15:50:41.106Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple announces Health Records feature coming to veterans]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/02/apple-announces-health-records-feature-coming-to-veterans/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple announces Health Records feature coming to veterans<br/>Working with the US Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), Apple announced that the Health Records on iPhone feature will be available soon to veterans. For the first time, American veterans receiving care through the Veterans Health Administration will be able to securely view their aggregated health records directly in the Health app on their iPhone.
<br/>“We have great admiration for veterans, and we’re proud to bring a solution like Health Records on iPhone to the veteran community,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “It’s truly an honor to contribute to the improved healthcare of America’s heroes.”
<br/>With Health Records on iPhone, veterans across the US will be able to see medical information from participating institutions — including the VA — organized into one view all in the Health app. Health records data includes allergies, conditions, immunizations, lab results, medications, procedures and vitals, and is displayed along with other information in the Health app like Apple Watch data. This means VA patients will get a single, integrated snapshot of their health profile whenever they want quickly and privately. All Health Records data is encrypted and protected with the user’s iPhone passcode, Touch ID or Face ID.
<br/>“When patients have better access to their health information, they have more productive conversations with their physicians,” said Jeff Williams, Apple’s COO. “By bringing Health Records on iPhone to VA patients, we hope veterans will experience improved healthcare that will enhance their lives.”
<br/>“Our goal is to empower people to better understand and improve their health, enabling them to view their medical information from multiple providers in one place easily and securely,” said Kevin Lynch, Apple’s vice president of Technology. “We’re excited to bring this feature to veterans across the US.”
<br/>Health Records on iPhone will be the first record-sharing platform of its kind available to the VA, which is the largest medical system in the United States providing service to more than 9 million veterans across 1,243 facilities.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Semonti Stephens,Apple,semonti_stephens@apple.com,(408) 974-8473<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Apple-iPhone-Xs-veterans-health-records-02112019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="American veterans receiving care through the Veterans Health Administration will be able to securely view their aggregated health records directly in the Health app on their iPhone." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-05T21:31:08.781Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple names Deirdre O’Brien senior vice president of Retail and People]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/02/apple-names-deirdre-obrien-senior-vice-president-of-retail-and-people/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple names Deirdre O’Brien senior vice president of Retail + People <br/>Angela Ahrendts Plans April Departure After Five Successful Years<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced that Deirdre O’Brien is taking on new responsibilities for Apple’s retail and online stores in an expanded role as senior vice president of Retail + People, reporting to CEO Tim Cook. After five transformative years leading the company’s retail and online stores, Angela Ahrendts plans to depart Apple in April for new personal and professional pursuits.
<br/>In her expanded role, Deirdre will bring her three decades of Apple experience to lead the company’s global retail reach, focused on the connection between the customer and the people and processes that serve them. She will continue to lead the People team, overseeing all People-related functions, including talent development and Apple University, recruiting, employee relations and experience, business partnership, benefits, compensation, and inclusion and diversity. 
<br/>“At Apple, we believe our soul is our people, and Deirdre understands the qualities and strengths of our team better than anyone,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “For more than three decades, she has helped keep Apple focused on serving customers and enriching lives. She’s an exceptional leader and she’s been a vital partner to our retail teams around the world since the very beginning. I am thrilled to work alongside Deirdre in her new role, and I know our 70,000 retail employees will be, too.”
<br/>“People come to Apple to do the best work of their lives, and our retail teams show their passion every day, in every interaction, all around the world,” said Deirdre O’Brien, senior vice president of Retail + People. “It is the opportunity of a lifetime to work with, and learn from, such a talented, diverse and imaginative team. I am looking forward to this journey, and to continuing the important work of the People team in supporting all of Apple’s amazing employees.”
<br/>Apple today operates 35 online stores and 506 retail stores on five continents, staffed by teams who are dedicated to enriching lives and serving their communities. Every Apple retail store location offers innovative programs for customers, including Today at Apple, designed to unlock creativity, inspire learning and encourage connection.
<br/>“I want to thank Angela for inspiring and energizing our teams over the past five years,” said Tim Cook. “She has been a positive, transformative force, both for Apple’s stores and the communities they serve. We all wish her the very best as she begins a new chapter.”
<br/>“The last five years have been the most stimulating, challenging and fulfilling of my career. Through the teams’ collective efforts, Retail has never been stronger or better positioned to make an even greater contribution for Apple,” said Angela Ahrendts, senior vice president of Retail. “I feel there is no better time to pass the baton to Deirdre, one of Apple’s strongest executives. I look forward to watching how this amazing team, under her leadership, will continue to change the world one person and one community at a time.”
<br/>Apple revolutionized personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Amy Bessette,Apple, abessette@apple.com,(408) 862-8012<br/>Nick Leahy,Apple,  nleahy@apple.com, (408) 862-5012<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/people/executives/Apple-Deirdre-OBrien-Apple-Park-02052019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple’s new Senior Vice President of Retail + People Deirdre O’Brien speaks to Apple employees on February 5, 2019." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/people/executives/Apple-Deirdre-OBrien-senior-vice-president-of-retail-and-people-02052019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Deirdre O’Brien, a 30-year Apple veteran, will lead Apple’s Retail and People teams." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-02-01T12:59:48.210Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple marks Heart Month in February]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/02/apple-marks-heart-month-in-february/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple marks Heart Month in February<br/>During Heart Month, Apple will offer an Activity Challenge on Apple Watch and heart health events in Apple Stores in San Francisco, Chicago and New York to educate consumers on their heart health and encourage them to get active and live a better day.
<br/>“Cardiovascular disease takes many forms and some are fully preventable through lifestyle changes like increased physical activity and better nutrition. It’s always great to see patients make those positive changes, especially with the help of Apple Watch,” said Sumbul Desai, MD, Apple’s vice president of Health. “Other conditions are more challenging to pinpoint like Afib and this is where we hope to help people access and understand information about their heart health through our irregular rhythm notification and ECG app.”
<br/>Atrial fibrillation (AFib) is the most common form of irregular heart rhythm and if left untreated can result in stroke. The Center for Disease Control (CDC) estimates AFib can affect up to two percent of the younger population and nine percent of those 65 years and older in the US. The ECG app and irregular rhythm notification feature were introduced on Apple Watch last year, which help users identify signs of AFib. Apple continues to receive letters from customers who explain Apple Watch has helped them identify heart conditions, seek medical treatment, lose weight and get more active.
<br/>“Apple Watch users have told us since the beginning it has motivated them with everything from Activity Sharing to Challenges to all of the different workouts available all right from the wrist,” said Jay Blahnik, Apple’s senior director of fitness for health technologies. “We hope this Activity Challenge and these conversations about heart health will motivate more customers to make regular physical activity a part of their lives.”
<br/>In recognition of Heart Month, Apple will host special Today at Apple sessions, “Heart Health with Apple,” in stores in New York, Chicago and San Francisco with celebrity fitness trainer Jeanette Jenkins, Sumbul Desai, MD, Apple’s vice president of Health, Nancy Brown, CEO of the American Heart Association, Jay Blahnik, senior director of fitness for health technologies, and Julz Arney and Craig Bolton from the Apple Fitness Technologies team. Attendees will hear a discussion about heart health and participate in a new Health &amp; Fitness Walk, which was co-created with Jeanette for participants to take a brisk walk with Apple Watch around their community.
<br/><ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.apple.com/today/event/exclusive-jeanette-jenkins-021119/6499418535969065833/" target="_blank">San Francisco</a>: </strong>Apple Union Square, February 11, 2019, 6 p.m.: Dr. Sumbul Desai, Jeanette Jenkins, Julz Arney</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.apple.com/today/event/exclusive-jeanette-jenkins-022119/6500795602807719277/?sn=R594" target="_blank">New York</a>: </strong>Apple Williamsburg, February 21, 2019, 4:30 p.m.: Dr. Sumbul Desai, Jeanette Jenkins, Jay Blahnik</li>
<li><strong>Chicago: </strong>Apple Michigan Avenue, February 27, 2019, 6 p.m.: Dr. Sumbul Desai, Nancy Brown, Jeanette Jenkins, Craig Bolton</li>
</ul>
<br/>Apple will offer a new Apple Watch Activity Challenge to promote heart health, where anyone who closes their Exercise Ring seven days in a row from February 8-14 will earn a special badge and stickers for Messages on Valentine’s Day.<sup>1</sup>
<br/>To register for a Heart Health with Apple session, visit <a href="http://apple.com/today" target="_blank">apple.com/today</a> or visit the Sessions tab in the Apple Store App.
<br/><sup>1</sup> In order to see the Activity challenge, users must update their iPhone to iOS 12.1.3 and Apple Watch to watchOS 5.1.3.<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Semonti Stephens,Apple,semonti_stephens@apple.com,(408) 974-8473<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/lifestyle/Apple-Heart-Health-Month-in-February-02012019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Celebrity fitness trainer Jeanette Jenkins co-created a Today at Apple session that helps attendees establish fun and healthy habits to stay motivated." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Apple-Watch-heart-month-sport-band-screen-01312019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple Watch users can earn a special badge for closing their Exercise Ring seven days in a row from February 8-14." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Apple-Watch-heart-month-badge-1-01312019_carousel.gif" rel="enclosure" title="Apple Watch users can earn a special badge for closing their Exercise Ring seven days in a row from February 8-14." type="image/gif"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Apple-Watch-heart-month-badge-2-01312019_carousel.gif" rel="enclosure" title="Apple Watch users can earn a special badge for closing their Exercise Ring seven days in a row from February 8-14." type="image/gif"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Apple-Watch-heart-month-badge-3-01312019_carousel.gif" rel="enclosure" title="Apple Watch users can earn a special badge for closing their Exercise Ring seven days in a row from February 8-14." type="image/gif"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Apple-Watch-Series-4-Sinus-Rhythm-screen-12062018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The ECG app and irregular rhythm notification feature launched last year, allowing Apple Watch users to monitor their heart health." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-30T12:58:42.326Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple Music takes flight on American Airlines]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/apple-music-takes-flight-on-american-airlines/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple Music takes flight on American Airlines<br/>Apple Music Subscribers can Stream Over 50 Million Songs, Playlists and Music Videos on US Flights<br/>Starting Friday, Apple Music subscribers can enjoy their access to over 50 million songs, playlists and music videos on any domestic American Airlines flight equipped with Viasat satellite Wi-Fi with no Wi-Fi purchase required. American Airlines is the first commercial airline to provide exclusive access to Apple Music through complimentary inflight Wi-Fi.
<br/>“For most travelers, having music to listen to on the plane is just as important as anything they pack in their suitcases,” said Oliver Schusser, vice president of Apple Music. “With the addition of Apple Music on American flights, we are excited that customers can now enjoy their music in even more places. Subscribers can stream all their favorite songs and artists in the air, and continue to listen to their personal library offline, giving them everything they need to truly sit back, relax and enjoy their flight.”
<br/>“Our guests want to make the most of their time when flying us. That’s why we’re investing in faster Wi-Fi, a variety of entertainment options, and why we’re so excited to introduce Apple Music to more of our customers,” said Janelle Anderson, vice president of Global Marketing at American. “Providing customers with more ways to stay connected throughout each flight is one way to show we value their business and the time they spend with us.”
<br/>Apple Music subscribers on American Airlines flights can enjoy the world’s most exciting new music and unique city-themed playlists for their journey, in addition to exclusive content such as in-depth artist interviews and today’s hottest sounds on the Beats 1 global livestream. To enjoy Apple Music during flight, customers on Viasat-equipped aircraft can connect to Wi-Fi at no cost and log in with their Apple Music subscription. Customers who don’t already have an Apple Music subscription can get Apple Music, sign up onboard and receive free access for three months. Apple Music is available on iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, Mac, Apple TV, PC, Android, CarPlay, HomePod, Sonos and Amazon Echo. &nbsp;
<br/>Visit <a href="https://applemusic.com/americanairlines/" target="_blank">applemusic.com/americanairlines</a> to learn more and listen onboard starting February 1.&nbsp;
<br/>Apple loves music. With iPod and iTunes, Apple revolutionized the music experience by putting a thousand songs in your pocket. Today, Apple Music takes this to the ultimate with over 50 million songs, thousands of playlists and daily selections from the world’s best music experts including Beats 1 Radio, a global live stream. Since 2015, Apple Music has welcomed tens of millions of subscribers in 115 countries. Streaming seamlessly to iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, Apple TV, Mac, HomePod and CarPlay, Apple Music is the most complete music experience on the planet.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Brian Bumbery,Apple,bumbery@apple.com,(424) 326-4156<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/music/standard/Apple-Music-takes-flight-on-American-Airlines-Playlist-animation-1-01302019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="On American Airlines, Apple Music subscribers can listen to curated playlists, such as The New Chicago, with no Wi-Fi purchase required." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/music/standard/Apple-Music-takes-flight-on-American_Airlines-Playlist_animation-01302019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="1. On any domestic American Airlines flight, connect to the complimentary inflight Wi-Fi and open Apple Music. 2. Listen to your library, the Beats 1 Global Livestream or curated playlists. 3. Sit back, relax and enjoy your flight." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-29T21:32:39.566Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple Reports First Quarter Results]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/apple-reports-first-quarter-results/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple Reports First Quarter Results<br/>Services, Mac and Wearables Set New All-Time Revenue Records<br/>EPS Reaches All-Time High at $4.18<br/>Cupertino, California — January 29, 2019 — Apple today announced financial results for its fiscal 2019 first quarter ended December 29, 2018. The Company posted quarterly revenue of $84.3 billion, a decline of 5 percent from the year-ago quarter, and quarterly earnings per diluted share of $4.18, up 7.5 percent. International sales accounted for 62 percent of the quarter’s revenue.
<br/>Revenue from iPhone® declined 15 percent from the prior year, while total revenue from all other products and services grew 19 percent. Services revenue reached an all-time high of $10.9 billion, up 19 percent over the prior year. Revenue from Mac® and Wearables, Home and Accessories also reached all-time highs, growing 9 percent and 33 percent, respectively, and revenue from iPad® grew 17 percent.
<br/>“While it was disappointing to miss our revenue guidance, we manage Apple for the long term, and this quarter’s results demonstrate that the underlying strength of our business runs deep and wide,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “Our active installed base of devices reached an all-time high of 1.4 billion in the first quarter, growing in each of our geographic segments. That’s a great testament to the satisfaction and loyalty of our customers, and it’s driving our Services business to new records thanks to our large and fast-growing ecosystem.”
<br/>“We generated very strong operating cash flow of $26.7 billion during the December quarter and set an all-time EPS record of $4.18,” said Luca Maestri, Apple’s CFO. “We returned over $13 billion to our investors during the quarter through dividends and share repurchases. Our net cash balance was $130 billion at the end of the quarter, and we continue to target a net cash neutral position over time.”
<br/>Apple is providing the following guidance for its fiscal 2019 second quarter:
<br/><ul style="list-style-position: inside;">
<li>revenue between $55 billion and $59 billion</li>
<li>gross margin between 37 percent and 38 percent</li>
<li>operating expenses between $8.5 billion and $8.6 billion</li>
<li>other income/(expense) of $300 million</li>
<li>tax rate of approximately 17 percent</li>
</ul>
<br/>Apple’s board of directors has declared a cash dividend of $0.73 per share of the Company’s common stock. The dividend is payable on February 14, 2019 to shareholders of record as of the close of business on February 11, 2019.
<br/>Apple will provide live streaming of its Q1 2019 financial results conference call beginning at 2:00 p.m. PST on January 29, 2019 at <a href="https://www.apple.com/investor/earnings-call/" target="_blank">www.apple.com/investor/earnings-call/</a>. This webcast will also be available for replay for approximately two weeks thereafter.
<br/>Apple periodically provides information for investors on its corporate website, <a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank">apple.com</a>, and its investors relations website, <a href="https://investor.apple.com/" target="_blank">investor.apple.com</a>. This includes press releases and other information about financial performance, reports filed or furnished with the SEC, information on corporate governance and details related to its annual meeting of shareholders.
<br/>This press release contains forward-looking statements, within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These forward-looking statements include without limitation those about the Company’s estimated revenue, gross margin, operating expenses, other income/(expense), tax rate, and plans for return of capital. These statements involve risks and uncertainties, and actual results may differ. Risks and uncertainties include without limitation: the effect of global and regional economic conditions on the Company's business, including effects on purchasing decisions by consumers and businesses; the ability of the Company to compete in markets that are highly competitive and subject to rapid technological change; the ability of the Company to manage frequent introductions and transitions of products and services, including delivering to the marketplace, and stimulating customer demand for, new products, services and technological innovations on a timely basis; the effect that shifts in the mix of products and services and in the geographic, currency or channel mix, component cost increases, price competition, or the introduction of new products, including new products with higher cost structures, could have on the Company’s gross margin; the dependency of the Company on the performance of distributors of the Company's products, including cellular network carriers and other resellers; the inventory and other asset risks associated with the Company’s need to order, or commit to order, product components in advance of customer orders; the continued availability on acceptable terms, or at all, of certain components, services and new technologies essential to the Company's business, including components and technologies that may only be available from single or limited sources; the dependency of the Company on manufacturing and logistics services provided by third parties, many of which are located outside of the US and which may affect the quality, quantity or cost of products manufactured or services rendered to the Company; the effect of product and services design and manufacturing defects on the Company’s financial performance and reputation; the dependency of the Company on third-party intellectual property and digital content, which may not be available to the Company on commercially reasonable terms or at all; the dependency of the Company on support from third-party software developers to develop and maintain software applications and services for the Company’s products; the impact of unfavorable legal proceedings, such as a potential finding that the Company has infringed on the intellectual property rights of others; the impact of changes to laws and regulations that affect the Company’s activities, including the Company’s ability to offer products or services to customers in different regions; the ability of the Company to manage risks associated with its international activities, including complying with laws and regulations affecting the Company’s international operations; the ability of the Company to manage risks associated with the Company’s retail stores; the ability of the Company to manage risks associated with the Company’s investments in new business strategies and acquisitions; the impact on the Company's business and reputation from information technology system failures, network disruptions or losses or unauthorized access to, or release of, confidential information; the ability of the Company to comply with laws and regulations regarding data protection; the continued service and availability of key executives and employees; political events, international trade disputes, war, terrorism, natural disasters, public health issues, and other business interruptions that could disrupt supply or delivery of, or demand for, the Company’s products; financial risks, including risks relating to currency fluctuations, credit risks and fluctuations in the market value of the Company’s investment portfolio; and changes in tax rates and exposure to additional tax liabilities. More information on these risks and other potential factors that could affect the Company’s financial results is included in the Company’s filings with the SEC, including in the “Risk Factors” and “Management’s Discussion and Analysis of Financial Condition and Results of Operations” sections of the Company’s most recently filed periodic reports on Form 10-K and Form 10-Q and subsequent filings. The Company assumes no obligation to update any forward-looking statements or information, which speak as of their respective dates.
<br/>Apple revolutionized personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contact <br/>Kristin Huguet,Apple,khuguet@apple.com,(408) 974-2414<br/>Investor Relations Contacts<br/>Nancy Paxton,Apple,paxton1@apple.com,(408) 974-5420<br/>Matt Blake,Apple,mattblake@apple.com,(408) 974-7406<br/>© 2019 Apple Inc. All rights reserved. Apple and the Apple logo are trademarks of Apple Inc. Other company and product names may be trademarks of their respective owners.<br/>
]]></content></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-29T18:02:48.773Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple announces new Today at Apple sessions]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/apple-announces-new-today-at-apple-sessions/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple announces new Today at Apple sessions<br/>Over 50 New Sessions Now Available<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced a new Today at Apple release with sessions in three new and expanded formats — Skills, Walks and Labs — which offer hands-on group sessions focused on photography, video, music, coding, app development, art and design and more. The new sessions are free at every Apple Store worldwide and allow visitors to find the right session for their interests and skill level in order to unlock their creativity, inspire learning and encourage connection.
<br/>Since the launch of Today at Apple in 2017, Apple has held over 18,000 free sessions a week attended by millions of participants around the world. This newest release expands on the most popular types of Today at Apple sessions, Walks and Labs, providing visitors even more opportunities to get more out of their products, find inspiration in their community and discover guidance from world-class creators.
<br/>“Since the beginning, Today at Apple has been about educating and inspiring the communities we serve. These new sessions are an opportunity to unlock the creative potential in all of our customers,” said Angela Ahrendts, Apple’s senior vice president of Retail. “There is a session for everyone at Today at Apple and we can’t wait to see what you will create.”<br />

<br/>Three Today at Apple session formats facilitate learning and creativity:
<br/><ul>
<li><strong>Skills</strong>&nbsp;are meant for those interested in learning new creative techniques to go further with our products, such as making a quick video with the Clips app or editing photos on iPhone. New Skills sessions include Notes and Chords with GarageBand, Sketching Ideas in Notes, Photo Editing Techniques and more.</li>
</ul>
<br/><ul>
<li><strong>Walks</strong> invite customers to venture outside of the store with a Creative Pro, where they will explore their surroundings, connect with their community and put new skills to use across passions like photography, music or health.&nbsp;New Walks include Capturing Cinematic Shots, Creating Soundscapes with GarageBand and a Health and Fitness Walk, Staying Motivated co-created with fitness expert Jeanette Jenkins.</li>
</ul>
<br/><ul>
<li><strong>Labs</strong> help customers experiment with creative techniques and complete the session with the beginning of a project. Many Labs have been co-created with world-renowned artists and makers. Building on the success of Labs with Florence Welch and photographer Chase Jarvis, skilled customers can find inspiration in new Labs like Beat Making with Swizz Beatz, Small Screen Magic with Zach King and Drawing Treehouses with Foster + Partners.</li>
</ul>
<br/>Today at Apple is also a great resource for families and kids of all ages interested in photography, coding, art and design and more. Labs like Fun Family Portraits, the Sphero Robot Obstacle Challenge and Make Your Own Emoji are built specifically to educate and spark creativity in younger visitors.<br />

<br/>Today at Apple includes sessions designed specifically for educators so teachers can learn new ways of bringing technology into their classroom, with Labs like App Design and Prototyping and Class Projects with Clips, based on the Everyone Can Code and Everyone Can Create curriculums.
<br/>To further enrich the Today at Apple experience in every store, Apple is upgrading the existing fleet of stores with design elements that greatly increase the store’s Today at Apple sessions and capacity. These upgrades include the addition of The Forum, an area of the store with a large video wall and seating, serving as a meeting place for the local community and home for Today at Apple. Some stores will add Avenues and, where possible, a grove of trees with integrated seating.<br />

<br/>To find and register for a new session, visit <a href="https://www.apple.com/today/" target="_blank">www.apple.com/today</a> or the Sessions tab in the Apple Store App.
<br/>Apple revolutionized personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Nick Leahy,Apple,  nleahy@apple.com, (408) 862-5012<br/>Ashley Rivera,Apple,ashley_rivera@apple.com,(408) 862-1381<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-today-at-Apple-sessions-Photo-lab-creating-photo-essays-01292019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="New Today at Apple sessions expand the possibilities for participants to find inspiration and create something new. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Photo-walk-framing-architecture-01292019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Photo Walks encourage visitors to find inspiration in their communities." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Art-skills-getting-started-Procreate-01292019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="At Skills sessions, attendees can learn and practice new creative techniques. " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Skills-01292019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A sample of the new Today at Apple lineup, featuring hands-on Skills, Walks and Labs sessions." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Walks-01292019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A sample of the new Today at Apple lineup, featuring hands-on Skills, Walks and Labs sessions." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Labs-01292019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A sample of the new Today at Apple lineup, featuring hands-on Skills, Walks and Labs sessions." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/environments/facilities/Apple-announces-new-Today-at-Apple-sessions-Music-lab-teachers-telling-stories-Garageband-01292019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Labs take place in the Forum, the heart of the store which serves as a meeting place for the local community and home for Today at Apple." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-28T18:02:59.093Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple Entrepreneur Camp kicks off as app developer earnings hit new record]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/apple-entrepreneur-camp-kicks-off-as-app-developer-earnings-hit-new-record/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple Entrepreneur Camp kicks off as app developer earnings hit new record<br/>Inaugural Session Provides Unprecedented Access to Apple Labs, Engineers, Business and Marketing Expertise<br><br>
App Developer Earnings Reach $120B Since 2008 App Store Launch<br/>Today, Apple opens its doors to 11 female-founded app development companies for the inaugural session of Entrepreneur Camp. The program is designed to provide female app creators with the tools needed to thrive in today’s global app economy. Since the App Store launched in 2008, developers have earned $120 billion, with more than a quarter of that in the past year alone.
<br/>An industry first, Entrepreneur Camp is a two-week immersive hands-on technology lab where participants work one-on-one with Apple experts and engineers to significantly accelerate their apps. The program also includes sessions on design, technology and App Store marketing, as well as ongoing guidance and support from an Apple Developer Relations representative. The curriculum will help developers take advantage of cutting-edge Apple technologies, including optimizing for the A12 Bionic chip, integrating Core ML, building new experiences with ARKit and more. Each participating company will also receive two tickets to WWDC and complementary membership to the Apple Developer Program for one year.
<br/>“The App Store is the new digital Main Street, and creative developers are tapping into the vast potential of the global app economy.”
<br/>“In the past, starting a small business often meant having to invest in overhead, inventory or retail space. Today, a world of opportunity opens up with some coding skills and an entrepreneurial spirit,” said Esther Hare, Apple’s senior director, Worldwide Developer Marketing and executive sponsor, Women@Apple. “The App Store is the new digital Main Street, and creative developers are tapping into the vast potential of the global app economy. We hope that this program helps to inspire women around the world to learn to code, join the iOS development community and share in the thriving app economy.”
<br/>The apps selected for the first session of Entrepreneur Camp are: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/bites/id1285503275?mt=8" target="_blank">Bites</a> by Warehouse Apps LLC; Camille by Ohhh, Inc.; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cuco-meds-pill-reminder/id1202953264?mt=8" target="_blank">CUCO: Lembrete de Medicamentos</a> by CUCO Health; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/deepr-dating-app/id1441236131?mt=8" target="_blank">Deepr</a>&nbsp;by Mental Mobile, LLC; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/defekt/id1367644508?mt=8" target="_blank">D’efekt</a> by Tatevik Gasparyan, Nané Toumanian and Vahagn Khachikyan; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hopscotch-coding-for-kids/id617098629?mt=8" target="_blank">Hopscotch</a> by Hopscotch Technologies; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/lactapp/id1040787494?mt=8" target="_blank">LactApp</a> by LactApp Women Health; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pureple-outfit-planner/id628106373?mt=8" target="_blank">Pureple</a>&nbsp;by Iceclip LLC; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/statues-of-the-la-paz-malec%C3%B3n/id1384303234?mt=8" target="_blank">Statues of the La Paz Malecón</a> by Estudio Chispa; <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/weparent-top-coparenting-app/id1441850251?mt=8" target="_blank">WeParent</a> by FamTerra Inc.; and <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/seneca-connect/id1350551544?mt=8" target="_blank">Seneca Connect</a> by Seneca Women.
<br/>Entrepreneur Camp will hold sessions on a quarterly basis, with up to 20 app companies accepted for each round. To be admitted to the program, app-driven businesses must be female founded, co-founded or led, and have at least one woman on the product development team. They must also have a working app or prototype. For more information on Apple Entrepreneur Camp or to apply, visit <a href="https://developer.apple.com/entrepreneur-camp/" target="_blank">developer.apple.com/entrepreneur-camp</a>.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Tammy Levine,Apple,tammy_levine@apple.com,(408) 862-8600<br/>Stephanie Saffer,Apple, ssaffer@apple.com ,(408) 974-5160 <br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-kicks-off-01282019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="From left: Livia Cunha, Nané Toumanian, and Tatevik Gasparyan are part of the inaugural class of Apple Entrepreneur Camp attendees arriving at Apple Park." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Kim-Azzarelli-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Kim Azzarelli, co-founder, Seneca Connect " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Suejung-Huh-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Suejung B. Huh, founder, Camille" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Livia-Cunha-01292019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Livia Cunha, CUCO: Lembrete de Medicamentos " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Roza-Ferdowsmakan-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Roza Ferdowsmakan, founder, Bites " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Elena-Krasnoperova-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Elena Krasnoperova, founder of WeParent" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Zhuo-Song-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Zhuo Song, developer, WeParent" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Cindy-Yates-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Cindy Yates, founder, Statues of the La Paz Malecón" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Fabiola-Werneck-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Fabiola Werneck, CTO, CUCO: Lembrete de Medicamentos  " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Enric-Roura-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Enric Roura, CEO, LactApp " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Alvar-Hernandez-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Àlvar Hernández, AI developer, LactApp" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Samantha-John-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Samantha John, CEO and co-founder, Hopscotch" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Nane-Toumanian-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Nané Toumanian, CEO and designer, D’efekt" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Maria-Berruezo-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Maria Berruezo, co-founder, LactApp" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Jung-Jin-Kang-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Jung Jin Kang, designer, Camille" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Tatevilk-Gasparyan-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Tatevik Gasparyan, founder and CTO, D’efekt " type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Rocio-Tovar-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Rocío Tovar, CTO, LactApp" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Renee-Olson-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Renee Olson, founder, Deepr" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Nazan-Kurt-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Nazan Kurt, founder, Pureple" type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-Entrepreneur-camp-Rodrigo-Tello-01282019_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Rodrigo Tello, designer, Hopscotch" type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-28T15:56:50.648Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Component manufacturing drives Apple’s US job creation]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/component-manufacturing-drives-apple-us-job-creation/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Component manufacturing drives Apple’s US job creation<br/>Just over a year ago, component manufacturer Finisar was awarded $390 million from <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2017/12/how-apple-and-finisar-are-transforming-the-future-of-this-texas-town/" target="_blank">Apple’s Advanced Manufacturing Fund</a>. To expand production of a critical part of the TrueDepth camera system, introduced with iPhone X, Finisar turned an unoccupied building in Sherman, Texas into a bustling operation full of people who will supply that future business.
<br/>Johnny Jackson, a 59-year-old machine operator, is one of the company’s new employees. After almost 30 years in the shipping industry, he moved to Sherman and was hired at Finisar.
<br/>“You take an old guy like me that’s been doing one job for 27 years, and now I’m learning something new every day,” says Jackson. “The training here is tremendous — you’ll be good because you’ve been trained by people who are good.”
<br/>In 2018, Apple spent $60 billion with 9,000 American component suppliers and companies, an increase of more than 10 percent from the year before, supporting more than 450,000 jobs.
<br/>Jackson’s new job is one of 500 being created as Finisar brings the Sherman facility back online. The plant will produce vertical-cavity surface-emitting lasers — or VCSELs — for Apple, powering breakthrough features of the latest iPhones and iPads, including Face ID and Animoji. VCSEL wafers are nearly as thin as a human hair and contain hundreds of layers measuring only a few atoms in thickness. They require a highly advanced and precise manufacturing operation, as well as skilled technicians with specialized training.<br>

<br/>Finisar is just one example of Apple’s expanding investment in US job growth and manufacturing. In 2018 alone, Apple spent $60 billion with 9,000 American component suppliers and companies, an increase of more than 10 percent from the year before, supporting more than 450,000 jobs.
<br/>The touch sensitive glass for iPhone and iPad is <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2017/05/apple-awards-corning-first-advanced-manufacturing-fund-investment/" target="_blank">made by Corning</a> at a 65-year-old facility in Harrodsburg, Kentucky. Cincinnati Test Systems in Ohio designed a first-of-its-kind equipment to ensure iPhone is water resistant. And Broadcom in Fort Collins, Colorado, Qorvo in Hillsboro, Oregon and Skyworks in Woburn, Massachusetts, are all making wireless communication hardware that enables global connectivity.
<br/>Since 2011, the total number of jobs created and supported by Apple in the United States has more than tripled — from almost 600,000 to 2 million across all 50 states.
<br/>Army veteran Michael Turner, 40, started as a process technician at Finisar’s Sherman facility in June. A father of two and grandfather of one, Turner is also a mentor for the AMP Program, an effort by local manufacturers to teach high school students about advanced manufacturing jobs and encourage them to explore future careers in the field.
<br/>Khan Qurashi, who was the first woman hired as an equipment engineering technician at Finisar’s Sherman plant, graduated with an associate degree in laser electro-optics in 2017. She says her new job will give her the opportunity to further develop her advanced manufacturing skills.
<br/>“I really like learning and I want to become a mechanical engineer,” says Qurashi. “And with Finisar, I can study for my degree and keep working for the company.”
<br/>As for Jackson, who has been on the job at Finisar since October, he feels like he’s been given a fresh start.
<br/>“New skills, new home, new job,” he says. “And a new outlook on life.”
<br/>Press Contact <br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/corporate/Apple-US-job-creation-Finisar-workers-01252019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Technicians at Finisar oversee VCSEL production at the Sherman, Texas facility." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/corporate/Apple-US-job-creation-Finisar-worker-01252019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Johnny Jackson started a new career with Finisar in October." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/corporate/Apple-US-job-creation-Finisar-technician-wafer-production-01252019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A Finisar technician handles a VCSEL wafer during production." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/corporate/Apple-US-job-creation-Finisar-workers-in-lab-01252019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Employees prepare the production floor in Sherman, Texas for additional manufacturing equipment." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/corporate/Apple-US-job-creation-Finisar-worker-getting-suited-up-01252019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Michael Turner gets ready to enter the production floor at the Sherman plant." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/corporate/Apple-US-job-creation-Finisar-Khan-Qurashi-01252019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Khan Qurashi is looking forward to a future in engineering with Finisar." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-24T17:58:17.124Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[The Mac App Store welcomes Office 365]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/the-mac-app-store-welcomes-office-365/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[The Mac App Store welcomes Office 365<br/>Today, Office 365 is available for the first time on the Mac App Store, making it easier than ever for Mac users to download Word, Outlook, Excel, PowerPoint, OneNote and the whole suite of Microsoft’s popular apps. Users can also purchase a subscription for <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app-bundle/id1450038993?mt=12" target="_blank">Office 365</a> from within the apps, so they can get up and running instantly.
<br/>Office 365 for Mac has been designed specifically to support features that are unique to the Mac experience — features like Dark Mode and Continuity Camera in macOS, as well as the MacBook Pro Touch Bar and the Mac’s industry-leading Trackpad.
<br/>“We are excited to welcome Microsoft Office 365 to the all new Mac App Store in macOS Mojave,” said Phil Schiller, Apple’s senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing. “Apple and Microsoft have worked together to bring great Office productivity to Mac users from the very beginning. Now, with Office 365 on the Mac App Store, it's easier than ever to get the latest and best version of Office 365 for Mac, iPad and iPhone.”
<br/>“We are excited to announce that today Office 365 is arriving in the Mac App Store,” said Jared Spataro, corporate vice president at Microsoft. “We have worked closely with Apple to provide Mac users with the very best productivity experience — one that offers everything they know and love about Office through an experience uniquely designed for the Mac.”
<br/>In business, as at home, employees want access to the best devices and apps to do their work. With Office 365 on the Mac App Store, these apps can now be easily distributed to employees using <a href="http://business.apple.com" target="_blank">Apple Business Manager</a>, a central dashboard where IT can deploy devices, apps and licenses. Now IT can quickly enable employees to get to work with their favorite Office tools across Mac, iPad and iPhone, with great new features designed specifically for Apple devices.
<br/>About the Mac App Store
<br/>The Mac App Store is the single largest catalog of Mac apps in the world. Newly redesigned this past year, the Mac App Store features a new look and rich editorial content for a more enjoyable experience when finding great, new apps for the Mac. Like the iOS App Store, the new Mac App Store celebrates apps, games, businesses and developers with an all-new Discover tab featuring compelling stories, in-depth interviews, helpful tips, collections of must-have apps and more. Users can also explore new Create, Work, Play and Develop tabs to find the perfect app for a specific project or purpose — from music, video and photography apps to business utilities and games.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Starlayne Meza,Apple, starlayne_meza@apple.com ,(408) 974-3391<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Office-365-now-available-on-mac-app-store-01242019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Microsoft Office 365 is now available on the Mac App Store for the first time." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Office-365-now-available-OneNote-mac-app-store-screen-01242019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Office 365 arrives on the Mac App Store following its recent redesign, featuring an all-new look and rich editorial content." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/apps/standard/Office-365-now-available-PowerPoint-app-screen-01242019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Office 365 apps, including PowerPoint, are specially designed to support the unique Mac experience." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-22T17:56:50.143Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Share your best photos shot on iPhone]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/share-your-best-photos-shot-on-iphone/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Share your best photos shot on iPhone<br/>Apple is kicking off 2019 by celebrating the most stunning photographs captured on iPhone, the world’s most popular camera, by inviting iPhone users to submit their best shots.
<br/>From January 22 to February 7, Apple is looking for outstanding photographs for a Shot on iPhone Challenge. A panel of judges will review worldwide submissions and select 10 winning photos, to be announced in February. The winning photos will be featured on billboards in select cities, Apple retail stores and online.
<br/>iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span>, iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span> Max, and iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span> bring innovations to photography, from sophisticated portraits with an adjustable depth of field, to Smart HDR which leverages multiple technologies — like faster sensors, an enhanced ISP and advanced algorithms — to bring more highlight and shadow detail to photos.<br/>Meet the Judges
<br/><strong>Pete Souza (US)</strong><br />
Pete was the chief official White House photographer for President Obama. His book, “Obama: An Intimate Portrait,” debuted as the #1 New York Times bestseller and is one of the best-selling photography books of all time.
<br/><strong>Austin Mann (US)</strong><br />
Austin is an iPhone photographer, filmmaker and creative who’s traveled around the world and has worked with numerous non-profit organizations to help better cast their vision worldwide. Austin has published iPhone photography reviews in outlets including National Geographic and CNN over the years.
<br/><strong>Annet de Graaf (Netherlands)</strong><br />
Graaf is a travel photographer who uses iPhone exclusively for her craft. She’s the author of two iPhone photography books: “Morning Amsterdam” and the upcoming “GO d’Azur,” the latter of which was shot entirely on iPhone 8 Plus. She’s taken portraits of Syrian ballet dancer Ahmad Joudeh as well as the late mayor of Amsterdam, Eberhard van der Laan.
<br/><strong>Luísa Dörr (Brazil)</strong><br />
Luísa is a photographer based in Brazil who rose to fame after she photographed TIME’s Firsts issue exclusively on iPhone. TIME won Documentary Project of the Year for the story in the prestigious Pictures of the Year International.
<br/><strong>Chen Man (China)</strong><br />
Chen is a Chinese contemporary visual artist and entrepreneur who created a unique visual language that revolutionized fashion photography in China. Her work has been permanently collected at the Victoria and Albert Museum in London and the Asian Art Museum in San Francisco. She also co-founded an Internet company called Vnision that developed photography-based social apps including Bigshot.
<br/><strong>Phil Schiller</strong><br />
Phil has helped Apple reinvent mobile phones with iPhone. A keen photographer, Phil helps with efforts in developing breakthrough camera technology as senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing.<br />

<br/><strong>Kaiann Drance</strong><br />
Kaiann works with talented teams at Apple to deliver products that put great photographic tools in the hands of many, including the first iPod touch with a camera and multiple generations of iPhone, in her role as senior director in Worldwide Product Marketing.
<br/><strong>Brooks Kraft</strong><br />
Brooks is a professional photographer and worked in editorial and commercial photography prior to joining Apple. He was a contributing photographer at TIME magazine, where he covered the White House during the Bush and Obama administrations, as well as seven presidential campaigns.
<br/><strong>Sebastien Marineau-Mes</strong><br>
Sebastien brings over 20 years of software development knowledge to iPhone in his role as vice president of Software at Apple. His focus on advanced photography features includes innovations like Smart HDR and Portrait mode with Depth Control.
<br/><strong>Jon McCormack</strong><br />
Jon is an accomplished photographer who currently leads Apple’s camera software team. Jon’s images have been published by international organizations including TIME, The New York Times, UNESCO, The Nature Conservancy, Africa Geographic and others.
<br/><strong>Arem Duplessis</strong><br />
Arem works closely with some of the most accomplished photographers in the world in his role as the director of photography in Apple’s marketing team. He previously served as design director of The New York Times Magazine for nearly a decade.
<br/>Submitting Your Best Shot
<br/>Post your best photo taken on iPhone to Instagram or Twitter with the #ShotOniPhone hashtag to participate in the the Shot on iPhone Challenge. Weibo users can participate as well using #ShotOniPhone#. In the image caption, note which model was used. Alternatively, you can also submit the photo in its highest resolution to shotoniphone@apple.com with the file format ‘firstname<em>lastname</em>iphonemodel.’ Photos can be straight from the camera, edited through Apple’s editing tools in the Photos app or with third-party software. Submissions for photos begins at 12:01 a.m. PST on January 22 and ends at 11:59 p.m. PST on February 7. You must be 18 years of age or older to participate, and this challenge is not open to Apple employees or their immediate families.
<br/>Ten winning photos will be featured on Apple Newsroom, Apple’s Instagram channels, <a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank">apple.com</a>, in Apple retail stores, Apple WeChat, Apple Twitter accounts, Apple Weibo accounts and billboards around the world. Winners will be notified on or about February 26, 2019.
<br/>If you’re submitting your photo on social media, you must make your photos public. Ineligible submissions include photos that violate or infringe upon another person’s rights, including but not limited to copyright, trademark, privacy, publicity or any other intellectual property rights or civil rights; contain sexually explicit, nude, obscene, violent or other objectionable or inappropriate content; or in any way disparage Apple or any other person or party.
<br/>You retain your rights to your photograph; however, by submitting your photo, you grant Apple a royalty-free, world-wide, irrevocable, non-exclusive license for one year to use, modify, publish, display, distribute, create derivative works from and reproduce the photo on Apple Newsroom, <a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank">apple.com</a>, Apple Twitter accounts, Apple Instagram (@Apple), in Apple retail stores, Apple Weibo, Apple WeChat, on billboards and any Apple internal exhibitions. Any photograph reproduced will include a photographer credit. If your photo is selected to be featured on a billboard, you further agree to grant Apple exclusive commercial use of the photo for the life of the license. Apple believes strongly that artists should be compensated for their work. Photographers who shoot the final 10 winning photos will receive a licensing fee for use of such photos on billboards and other Apple marketing channels.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Andrew Kelly,Apple,andrewkelly@apple.com,(669) 283-1423<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/Shot-on-iPhone-Challenge-Announcement-Woman-in-front-of-Petra_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Shot on iPhone 7 by Erdem Summak." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/Shot-on-iPhone-Challenge-Announcement-Forest_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Shot on iPhone 6s by Mariko Klug." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/Shot-on-iPhone-Challenge-Announcement-Swimming-in-water_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Shot on iPhone 6 by Mandy Blake." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-22T13:56:42.782Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[Apple Pay coming to Target, Taco Bell and more top US retail locations]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/apple-pay-coming-to-target-taco-bell-and-more-top-us-retail-locations/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Apple Pay coming to Target, Taco Bell and more top US retail locations<br/>Seventy-Four of the Top 100 US Merchants Now Accept Apple Pay<br/>Target, Taco Bell, Hy-Vee supermarkets in the Midwest, Speedway convenience stores and Jack in the Box are the latest merchants to support Apple Pay, the most popular mobile contactless payment system in the world that lets customers easily and securely pay in stores using their iPhone and Apple Watch. With the addition of these national retailers, 74 of the top 100 merchants in the US and 65 percent of all retail locations across the country will support Apple Pay.
<br/>“Whether customers are buying everyday household items, groceries, snacks for a road trip or grabbing a quick meal, Apple Pay is the easiest way to pay in stores, while also being secure and faster than using a credit or debit card at the register,” said Jennifer Bailey, Apple’s vice president of Internet Services. “We’re thrilled even more customers will be able to pay at their favorite stores and restaurants using the Apple devices that are always with them.”<br />

<br/>Apple Pay is rolling out now in Target stores and will be available in all 1,850 locations across the US in the coming weeks. Customers can use Apple Pay today at more than 245 Hy-Vee stores in the Midwest and inside the store at all of Speedway’s approximately 3,000 locations across the Midwest, East Coast and Southeast. Apple Pay is also rolling out to more than 7,000 Taco Bell and 2,200 Jack in the Box locations in the next few months.
<br/>These top merchants join other national retailers that already support Apple Pay. In 2018, Costco completed the rollout of Apple Pay to over 500 US warehouses and CVS Pharmacy introduced Apple Pay at all of its nearly 8,400 stand-alone locations. 7-Eleven launched Apple Pay at 95 percent of its US stores last year.&nbsp;
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Hannah Wong,Apple,hannahw@apple.com,(408) 974-7077<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/services/standard/Apple-Pay-coming-to-partners-Customer-checking-out-with-Apple-Pay-at-Target-01222019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple Pay is an easy, secure and private way to pay using iPhone and Apple Watch that’s fast and convenient." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/services/standard/Apple-Pay-coming-to-Partners-logo-grid-01222019_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Just some of the top US merchants accepting Apple Pay at millions of locations across the country. " type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-21T15:00:26.295Z]]></updated><category term="FEATURE"/><title><![CDATA[Out of a culture of giving, a world of difference]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/out-of-a-culture-of-giving-a-world-of-difference/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Out of a culture of giving, a world of difference<br/>How Apple Volunteers are Helping Transform Lives<br/>Fourteen-year-old Michael Normoyle jumps out of his chair to write his cipher on the board: <em>ZLANZRVFZVPUNRY.</em>
<br/>The rest of the class starts furiously scribbling at their desks, hoping to be the first to solve the puzzle.
<br/>In coding class at Terence MacSwiney School in Cork, Ireland, things tend to get very competitive among this group of fourteen and fifteen year olds. That’s especially true for Normoyle and classmates Seán Harris and Michael McGlue — all three are vying to be named the year’s standout coding student.
<br/>The program is part of a special initiative made possible by Apple volunteers from the company’s nearby Cork campus. Once a week, more than a dozen volunteers visit the school to help teach coding, drawing, photography, music and video. Since the program began three years ago, the school — one of the most economically disadvantaged in Ireland — and its students have been transformed.
<br/>It’s one of thousands of organizations where Apple employees volunteer their time. And for every hour an employee gives, or dollar they donate, Apple provides matching funds for both. In 2018, that added up to more than a quarter of a million hours volunteered and more than $125 million donated to organizations around the world.
<br/>That includes China, where Apple is one of the only global companies matching employee donations. Thirty-two Chinese charitable organizations are now eligible to receive funds, including the China Foundation for Poverty Alleviation, which aided more than 175,000 people across 24 provinces with disaster relief and preparedness in 2018 alone.
<br/>“You have to create hope, no matter what context you work in. Sometimes you need a bit of help with that.”
<br/>All told, since its inception eight years ago, Apple’s Giving program has become a powerful force for global good, raising more than $365 million for nonprofits around the world. Though if you ask the people whose lives have been changed by these efforts, they’ll tell you that the benefit can be measured in so much more than dollars and cents.
<br/>“We have a lot of students that have the odds stacked against them,” says Terence MacSwiney’s Principal Phil O’Flynn. “But this program has helped nurture them, and we’ve discovered talents that we never knew they had.”
<br/>Before they started the program, Normoyle, Harris and McGlue never expected their future careers to involve coding. All three would be the first in their families to complete a post-secondary degree, something their teacher Linda Cagney and Principal O’Flynn say is now well within their reach.
<br/>“You have to create hope, no matter what context you work in,” says O’Flynn. “Sometimes you need a bit of help with that, and that’s what this program does — it lifts the school.”
<br/>Back in coding class, students are still trying to decipher Normoyle’s cipher. Eventually, someone shouts out: “My name is Michael.” 
<br/>He smiles, and confirms that’s exactly right.
<br/><center><em>*</em></center>
<br/>Lauren Cook, 24, was a senior at San Jose State University in 2017, working four jobs to make ends meet when she saw a flyer advertising a Second Harvest food pantry at the school. She left with more than bags full of fresh produce.
<br/>“Second Harvest helped me become the person I am today — sorry, I’m getting a little emotional,” says Cook, through tears. “It meant I had to work only one job, and it allowed me to focus on being a college student.”
<br/>Since the Great Recession in 2008, the number of people served each month by Second Harvest Food Bank in Santa Clara and San Mateo Counties, which include most of Silicon Valley, has seen a 47 percent jump — from an average of 175,000 to 260,000. In 2018 alone that translated to almost 55 million meals.
<br/>Apple’s history of volunteering with Second Harvest goes back to 2000. Last year, its employees spent almost 3000 hours sorting and distributing food, which makes the food bank one of the largest recipients of Apple volunteer hours in the US.&nbsp;
<br/>“What’s so important about this partnership is that we have Apple volunteers that we can depend on,” said Second Harvest CEO Leslie Bacho. “That long-term commitment makes it possible to try new things and innovate, which includes our food pantries at colleges. It’s what gives me hope that if there’s anywhere in the country we can solve hunger, it would be here.”
<br/><center><em>*</em></center>
<br/>When Samuel Snowe, 29, opened the package containing his chest binder, he was surprised to find something else.
<br/>“Be the person you want to be,” the note began. “Loving yourself is the first step. Thank you for being your amazing self.”
<br/>It was signed only, ‘Megan.’ Snowe was overcome with emotion — those twenty one words reminded him he wasn’t alone.&nbsp;
<br/>In 2009, Aydian Dowling came out as transgender, but medical insurance wouldn’t cover his transition. He eventually raised enough funds on his own and with the support of friends, but the negative experience left him wanting to help others. Two years ago, he co-founded Point of Pride, whose mission statement is “to benefit trans people in need through gender-affirming support programs that empower them to live more authentically.”
<br/>That includes the organization’s apparel program, which has sent out more than 3500 free chest binders to people around the world including Snowe, along with a personal note of encouragement.
<br/>The idea to include a note began when the organization linked up with Apple employee Liz Byrne, who now sits on Point of Pride’s board. Liz received a letter of encouragement from a close friend while going through a difficult time in high school. Liz has since organized almost 20 writing sessions at Apple’s Cupertino, Austin and Sacramento campuses, attended by hundreds of employees.&nbsp;
<br/>For Snowe, receiving the free binder was essential, but he credits the note with even more. 
<br/>“Being transgender, there’s a lot of moments where you don’t feel like you deserve to be alive — like you’re less of a human,” says Snowe. “And things like this remind us that we’re still human, we’re still alive, we’re still people, and we’re important to somebody.” 
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-student-Ericka-Lingwood-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Terence MacSwiney School student Ericka Lingwood has developed her animation skills as part of the Apple volunteer program." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-student-Micheal-Normoyle-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Terence MacSwiney School student Michael Normoyle writes his cipher on the board in coding class, while Apple volunteer Pavel Zizka looks on." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-students-in-many-subjects-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple volunteers work with students across a range of subjects, including photography." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Principal-Phil-O-Flynn-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Terence MacSwiney School Principal Phil O’Flynn has seen a dramatic change in her students since the Apple volunteer initiative began." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Teacher-Linda-Cagney-assists-students-in-ciphers-coding-class-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Terence MacSwiney teacher Linda Cagney assists students Michael McGlue and Seán Harris as they work solving ciphers in coding class." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Second-Harvest-Lauren-Cook-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Lauren Cook credits Second Harvest with giving her the chance to focus on college and her future." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Second-Harvest-01212019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Apple volunteers sort oranges at Second Harvest Food Bank in San Jose, California." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-letter-of-encouragement-from-Point-of-Pride-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="An example of a letter of encouragement from Point of Pride." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Point-of-Pride-letter-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="An example of a letter of encouragement from Point of Pride." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Point-of-Pride-note-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="An example of a letter of encouragement from Point of Pride." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Aydian-Dowling-co-founded-Point-of-Pride-to-help-trans-community-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Aydian Dowling co-founded Point of Pride to help other members of the trans community." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-Liz-Byrne-01212019_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Liz Byrne has helped organize letter writing sessions at Apple that are open to all employees." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/diversity-inclusion/Apple-volunteer-program-note-Liz-Byrne-Point-of-Pride-letter-writing-program_big_carousel.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="The note that Liz Byrne received from a friend in high school that became the inspiration for Point of Pride’s letter writing program." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-13T21:56:44.939Z]]></updated><category term="UPDATE"/><title><![CDATA[HomePod available in China starting Friday, January 18]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/HomePod-available-in-china-starting-friday-january-18/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[HomePod available in China starting Friday, January 18<br/>Breakthrough Wireless Speaker Delivers an Immersive Listening Experience with High-Fidelity Sound<br/>HomePod, the innovative wireless speaker from Apple, will be available in mainland China and Hong Kong markets starting Friday, January 18. <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/01/homepod-arrives-february-9-available-to-order-this-friday/" target="_blank">HomePod</a> delivers stunning audio quality wherever it’s placed, playing any style of music. It’s easy and fun for everyone to use in the home, provides unmatched stereo sound with a stereo pair that offers a wider, <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/05/ios-11-4-brings-stereo-pairs-and-multi-room-audio-with-airplay-2/" target="_blank">more immersive soundstage</a> than traditional stereo speakers, and works together with an Apple Music subscription to stream millions of songs directly to HomePod.
<br/>HomePod supports AirPlay 2, creating an effortless way for people to stream audio content from popular apps and services directly from an iOS device to HomePod and still experience breakthrough audio quality, whether listening to an audiobook, live radio or other popular music services.
<br/>“HomePod is the perfect wireless speaker for music lovers. It delivers an unmatched music listening experience with high-fidelity sound wherever it is placed and creates a new way to discover and interact with music using Siri,” said Philip Schiller, Apple’s senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing. “We’re excited to bring HomePod to our customers in mainland China and Hong Kong markets. We can’t wait for them to experience how great it sounds in their home, we think they are going to love it.”
<br/>HomePod combines Apple-engineered audio technology and advanced software to set a new audio quality standard for a small speaker. Featuring an Apple-designed woofer for deep, clean bass, a custom array of seven beamforming tweeters that provide pure high frequency acoustics with incredible directional control and powerful technologies built right in, HomePod is able to preserve the richness and intent of the original recordings.
<br/>HomePod is designed for voice control with an array of six microphones, so everyone in the family can interact with it from across the room, even while loud music is playing. Apple Music learns personal preferences based on the songs a user listens to and likes and these music tastes are shared across devices. Ask Siri to “play something I like” or choose from a variety of moods and genres such as Mandopop and Cantopop. HomePod, Apple Music and Siri deliver the best ad-free music experience in the home.
<br/>The New Artist of the Week program provides new talent with a prominent platform across greater China for their work to be discovered. Since launching in 2015, Apple Music has featured the debut releases of popular new artists coming from all over Asia, with music spanning a wide variety of genres and languages. New artists from mainland China include Corsak, Chace, Lucie Cheung, Gong, Dean Ting and Lu Xianghui. Popular playlists include The A-List International Pop, Today’s Hits, Best of the Week, The A-List Mandopop and Mandopop Replay, containing recent Mandopop hits from the past five years.
<br/>HomePod delivers an even more immersive listening experience when two HomePod speakers become a stereo pair, delivering high-fidelity sound with a wide soundstage. Using spatial awareness to sense their location in the room, each HomePod automatically adjusts the audio to sound great wherever it is placed and sound great together. And with AirPlay 2, it’s easy to stream music and other audio content from any AirPlay-supported apps, including QQ Music, DeDao, iHuman Story, Dragonfly FM and Penguin FM in mainland China, and Spotify, KKBOX, JOOX and Podcast in Hong Kong, and still experience high-fidelity sound from HomePod.
<br/>AirPlay 2 delivers the best wireless multi-room audio system and makes it easy to play and control music throughout the house with a powerful yet simple interface that works across any AirPlay-compatible speakers and TVs. It’s easy to play music in another room, move music from one room to another or play the same song on multiple HomePod speakers. AirPlay 2 controls are available across iOS within any app and in Control Center for quick access to what’s playing in every room, on every speaker.
<br/>HomePod is a convenient way to check the weather or the latest sports scores, set multiple timers and reminders, <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/09/homepod-adds-new-features-and-siri-languages/" target="_blank">make and receive phone calls</a> and more. In China, Siri on HomePod also offers storytelling for children, just say “Hey Siri, tell me a story.” As a smart home hub, HomePod controls a wide range of <a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/home/" target="_blank">HomeKit</a> smart home accessories, including lights, air quality monitors, door locks, security cameras and more, from over 50 brands worldwide.<sup>1 </sup>Simply say, “Hey Siri, what’s the air quality in my home?” or “Hey Siri, turn on the lights in the kitchen and living room.”
<br/>Siri Shortcuts, introduced with iOS 12, open up a world of apps to work on HomePod. As Siri learns routines and suggests “shortcuts” on iPhone and iPad, these same shortcuts are now accessible on HomePod. Personalizing shortcuts for HomePod with a series of tasks is easy with a new Shortcuts app. For example, “Hey Siri, Good Morning” could run a routine that turns on the kitchen lights, starts the water kettle, shares the weather forecast and then plays a favorite playlist — all with one simple, customizable command.
<br/>Security and privacy are fundamental to the design of Apple hardware, software and services. With HomePod, only after “Hey Siri” is recognized locally on the device will any information be sent to Apple servers, encrypted and sent using an anonymous Siri identifier. Searches and requests are not associated with a specific identity, so personal information isn’t gathered to sell to advertisers or other organizations. End-to-end encryption ensures that data cannot be accessed, even by Apple. Personal requests, such as the ability to send messages, make phone calls, check calendar appointments and more, are only available if the feature is turned on in Settings and the iOS device is on the same network as HomePod.
<br/>HomePod will be available starting Friday, January 18 in mainland China and Hong Kong markets in white and space gray. HomePod is available in the US, UK, Australia, Canada, France, Germany, Mexico and Spain. HomePod is compatible with iPhone 5s or later, iPad Pro, iPad Air or later, iPad mini 2 or later, or iPod touch (6th generation).
<br/><sup>1</sup> HomeKit accessories may not be available in all areas.<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Jacqueline Roy,Apple,jacqueline_roy@apple.com ,(408) 862-4386<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/homepod/standard/HomePod-arrives-in-China-black-HomePod-12042018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="HomePod automatically senses its location in the room to deliver immersive room-filling sound wherever it is placed." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/homepod/standard/HomePod-white-2-12042018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="A stereo pair creates an even wider soundstage for an incredible listening experience on HomePod." type="image/jpeg"/><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/homepod/standard/Homepod_Siri-12042018_inline.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Use HomePod with Siri from across the room to listen to Apple Music, control HomeKit accessories and more." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-03T17:02:41.582Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[App Store caps record-breaking 2018 with blockbuster holiday week]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/app-store-caps-record-breaking-2018-with-blockbuster-holiday-week/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[App Store caps record-breaking 2018 with blockbuster holiday week<br/>Customers Spent $1.22B During the 2018 Holiday and Kicked off 2019 With a New Single-Day Record on New Year’s Day<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced that App Store customers worldwide set new spending records over the holidays, wrapping up a record-breaking year. App Store spending topped $1.22 billion between Christmas Eve and New Year’s Eve. Customers also spent over $322 million on New Year’s Day 2019 alone, setting a new single-day record.
<br/>“The App Store had a record-breaking holiday week and New Year's Day. The holiday week was our biggest week ever with more than $1.22 billion spent on apps and games, and New Year’s Day set a new single-day record at more than $322 million,” said Phil Schiller, Apple’s senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing. “Thanks to the inspiring work of our talented developers and the support of our incredible customers around the world, the App Store finished off an outstanding 2018 and kicked off 2019 with a bang.”
<br/>Apple announced Wednesday that the App Store helped drive Services revenue to an all-time record in the holiday quarter. Apple services set new all-time records in multiple categories, including the App Store, Apple Music, Cloud Services, Apple Pay and the App Store’s search ad business.<br />

<br/>Gaming and self-care were the most popular categories of app downloads and subscriptions during the holidays. Globally, multiplayer games including Fortnite and PUBG were among the top downloaded games over the holidays, along with Brawl Stars, Asphalt 9 and Monster Strike. Productivity, Health &amp; Fitness and Education apps are already capturing the attention of customers in the first few days of the year with 1Password, Sweat and Lumosity charting in their respective categories.<br>

<br/>Apple revolutionized personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.<br />

<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Stephanie Saffer,Apple, ssaffer@apple.com ,(408) 974-5160 <br/>Tammy Levine,Apple,tammy_levine@apple.com,(408) 862-8600<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/app-store/App-Store-caps-record-breaking-2018-with-blockbuster-holiday-week-01032019_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Customers spent over $322 million in the App Store on New Year’s Day 2019 alone, setting a new single-day record." type="image/jpeg"/></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2019-01-02T21:32:39.287Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[Letter from Tim Cook to Apple investors]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/01/letter-from-tim-cook-to-apple-investors/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Letter from Tim Cook to Apple investors<br/>January 2, 2019<br>

<br/>To Apple investors:
<br/>Today we are revising our guidance for Apple’s fiscal 2019 first quarter, which ended on December 29. We now expect the following:
<br/><ul>
<li>Revenue of approximately $84 billion</li>
<li>Gross margin of approximately 38 percent</li>
<li>Operating expenses of approximately $8.7 billion</li>
<li>Other income/(expense) of approximately $550 million</li>
<li>Tax rate of approximately 16.5 percent before discrete items</li>
</ul>
<br/>We expect the number of shares used in computing diluted EPS to be approximately 4.77 billion.
<br/>Based on these estimates, our revenue will be lower than our original guidance for the quarter, with other items remaining broadly in line with our guidance. 
<br/>While it will be a number of weeks before we complete and report our final results, we wanted to get some preliminary information to you now. Our final results may differ somewhat from these preliminary estimates. 
<br/>When we discussed our Q1 guidance with you about 60 days ago, we knew the first quarter would be impacted by both macroeconomic and Apple-specific factors. Based on our best estimates of how these would play out, we predicted that we would report slight revenue growth year-over-year for the quarter. As you may recall, we discussed four factors:
<br/>First, we knew the different timing of our iPhone launches would affect our year-over-year compares. Our top models, iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span> and iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span> Max, shipped in Q4’18—placing the channel fill and early sales in that quarter, whereas last year iPhone X shipped in Q1’18, placing the channel fill and early sales in the December quarter. We knew this would create a difficult compare for Q1’19, and this played out broadly in line with our expectations.
<br/>Second, we knew the strong US dollar would create foreign exchange headwinds and forecasted this would reduce our revenue growth by about 200 basis points as compared to the previous year. This also played out broadly in line with our expectations.
<br/>Third, we knew we had an unprecedented number of new products to ramp during the quarter and predicted that supply constraints would gate our sales of certain products during Q1. Again, this also played out broadly in line with our expectations. Sales of Apple Watch Series 4 and iPad Pro were constrained much or all of the quarter. AirPods and MacBook Air were also constrained.
<br/>Fourth, we expected economic weakness in some emerging markets. This turned out to have a significantly greater impact than we had projected. 
<br/>In addition, these and other factors resulted in fewer iPhone upgrades than we had anticipated. 
<br/>These last two points have led us to reduce our revenue guidance. I’d like to go a bit deeper on both. 
<br/><strong>Emerging Market Challenges</strong>
<br/>While we anticipated some challenges in key emerging markets, we did not foresee the magnitude of the economic deceleration, particularly in Greater China. In fact, most of our revenue shortfall to our guidance, and over 100 percent of our year-over-year worldwide revenue decline, occurred in Greater China across iPhone, Mac and iPad.
<br/>China’s economy began to slow in the second half of 2018. The government-reported GDP growth during the September quarter was the second lowest in the last 25 years. We believe the economic environment in China has been further impacted by rising trade tensions with the United States. As the climate of mounting uncertainty weighed on financial markets, the effects appeared to reach consumers as well, with traffic to our retail stores and our channel partners in China declining as the quarter progressed. And market data has shown that the contraction in Greater China’s smartphone market has been particularly sharp.
<br/>Despite these challenges, we believe that our business in China has a bright future. The iOS developer community in China is among the most innovative, creative and vibrant in the world. Our products enjoy a strong following among customers, with a very high level of engagement and satisfaction. Our results in China include a new record for Services revenue, and our installed base of devices grew over the last year. We are proud to participate in the Chinese marketplace.
<br/><strong>iPhone</strong>
<br/>Lower than anticipated iPhone revenue, primarily in Greater China, accounts for all of our revenue shortfall to our guidance and for much more than our entire year-over-year revenue decline. In fact, categories outside of iPhone (Services, Mac, iPad, Wearables/Home/Accessories) combined to grow almost 19 percent year-over-year. 
<br/>While Greater China and other emerging markets accounted for the vast majority of the year-over-year iPhone revenue decline, in some developed markets, iPhone upgrades also were not as strong as we thought they would be. While macroeconomic challenges in some markets were a key contributor to this trend, we believe there are other factors broadly impacting our iPhone performance, including consumers adapting to a world with fewer carrier subsidies, US dollar strength-related price increases, and some customers taking advantage of significantly reduced pricing for iPhone battery replacements. 
<br/><strong>Many Positive Results in the December Quarter</strong>
<br/>While it’s disappointing to revise our guidance, our performance in many areas showed remarkable strength in spite of these challenges. 
<br/>Our installed base of active devices hit a new all-time high—growing by more than 100 million units in 12 months. There are more Apple devices being used than ever before, and it’s a testament to the ongoing loyalty, satisfaction and engagement of our customers. 
<br/>Also, as I mentioned earlier, revenue outside of our iPhone business grew by almost 19 percent year-over-year, including all-time record revenue from Services, Wearables and Mac. Our non-iPhone businesses have less exposure to emerging markets, and the vast majority of Services revenue is related to the size of the installed base, not current period sales. 
<br/>Services generated over $10.8 billion in revenue during the quarter, growing to a new quarterly record in every geographic segment, and we are on track to achieve our goal of doubling the size of this business from 2016 to 2020.
<br/>Wearables grew by almost 50 percent year-over-year, as Apple Watch and AirPods were wildly popular among holiday shoppers; launches of MacBook Air and Mac mini powered the Mac to year-over-year revenue growth and the launch of the new iPad Pro drove iPad to year-over-year double-digit revenue growth. 
<br/>We also expect to set all-time revenue records in several developed countries, including the United States, Canada, Germany, Italy, Spain, the Netherlands and Korea. And, while we saw challenges in some emerging markets, others set records, including Mexico, Poland, Malaysia and Vietnam.
<br/>Finally, we also expect to report a new all-time record for Apple’s earnings per share.
<br/><strong>Looking Ahead</strong>
<br/>Our profitability and cash flow generation are strong, and we expect to exit the quarter with approximately $130 billion in net cash. As we have stated before, we plan to become net-cash neutral over time.
<br/>As we exit a challenging quarter, we are as confident as ever in the fundamental strength of our business. We manage Apple for the long term, and Apple has always used periods of adversity to re-examine our approach, to take advantage of our culture of flexibility, adaptability and creativity, and to emerge better as a result. 
<br/>Most importantly, we are confident and excited about our pipeline of future products and services. Apple innovates like no other company on earth, and we are not taking our foot off the gas.
<br/>We can’t change macroeconomic conditions, but we are undertaking and accelerating other initiatives to improve our results. One such initiative is making it simple to trade in a phone in our stores, finance the purchase over time, and get help transferring data from the current to the new phone. This is not only great for the environment, it is great for the customer, as their existing phone acts as a subsidy for their new phone, and it is great for developers, as it can help grow our installed base. 
<br/>This is one of a number of steps we are taking to respond. We can make these adjustments because Apple’s strength is in our resilience, the talent and creativity of our team, and the deeply held passion for the work we do every day.
<br/>Expectations are high for Apple because they should be. We are committed to exceeding those expectations every day.
<br/>That has always been the Apple way, and it always will be.
<br/>Tim
<br/>The information presented in this letter is preliminary and our actual results may differ. Apple plans to discuss final results during our first quarter conference call on Tuesday, January 29, 2019 at 2:00 p.m. PST / 5:00 p.m. EST.
<br/>This letter contains forward-looking statements, within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These forward-looking statements include without limitation those about Apple’s estimated revenue, gross margin, operating expenses, other income/(expense), tax rate, net cash, share count and plans for return of capital. These statements involve risks and uncertainties, and actual results may differ. Risks and uncertainties include without limitation: the effect of global and regional economic conditions on Apple’s business, including effects on purchasing decisions by consumers and businesses; the ability of Apple to compete in markets that are highly competitive and subject to rapid technological change; the ability of Apple to manage frequent introductions and transitions of products and services, including delivering to the marketplace, and stimulating customer demand for, new products, services and technological innovations on a timely basis; the effect that shifts in the mix of products and services and in the geographic, currency or channel mix, component cost increases, price competition, or the introduction of new products, including new products with higher cost structures, could have on Apple’s gross margin; the dependency of Apple on the performance of distributors of Apple’s products, including cellular network carriers and other resellers; the inventory and other asset risks associated with Apple’s need to order, or commit to order, product components in advance of customer orders; the continued availability on acceptable terms, or at all, of certain components, services and new technologies essential to Apple’s business, including components and technologies that may only be available from single or limited sources; the dependency of Apple on manufacturing and logistics services provided by third parties, many of which are located outside of the US and which may affect the quality, quantity or cost of products manufactured or services rendered to Apple; the effect of product and services design and manufacturing defects on Apple’s financial performance and reputation; the dependency of Apple on third-party intellectual property and digital content, which may not be available to Apple on commercially reasonable terms or at all; the dependency of Apple on support from third-party software developers to develop and maintain software applications and services for Apple’s products; the impact of unfavorable legal proceedings, such as a potential finding that Apple has infringed on the intellectual property rights of others; the impact of changes to laws and regulations that affect Apple’s activities, including Apple’s ability to offer products or services to customers in different regions; the ability of Apple to manage risks associated with its international activities, including complying with laws and regulations affecting Apple’s international operations; the ability of Apple to manage risks associated with Apple’s retail stores; the ability of Apple to manage risks associated with Apple’s investments in new business strategies and acquisitions; the impact on Apple’s business and reputation from information technology system failures, network disruptions or losses or unauthorized access to, or release of, confidential information; the ability of Apple to comply with laws and regulations regarding data protection; the continued service and availability of key executives and employees; political events, international trade disputes, war, terrorism, natural disasters, public health issues, and other business interruptions that could disrupt supply or delivery of, or demand for, Apple’s products; financial risks, including risks relating to currency fluctuations, credit risks and fluctuations in the market value of Apple’s investment portfolio; and changes in tax rates and exposure to additional tax liabilities. More information on these risks and other potential factors that could affect Apple’s financial results is included in Apple’s filings with the SEC, including in the “Risk Factors” and “Management’s Discussion and Analysis of Financial Condition and Results of Operations” sections of Apple’s most recently filed periodic reports on Form 10-K and Form 10-Q and subsequent filings. Apple assumes no obligation to update any forward-looking statements or information, which speak as of their respective dates.
<br/>Apple revolutionized personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.
<br/>Press Contact<br/>Josh Rosenstock,Apple,jrosenstock@apple.com,(408) 862-1142<br/>Investor Relations Contacts<br/>Nancy Paxton,Apple,paxton1@apple.com,(408) 974-5420<br/>Matt Blake,Apple,mattblake@apple.com,(408) 974-7406<br/>© 2019 Apple Inc. All rights reserved. Apple and the Apple logo are trademarks of Apple Inc. Other company and product names may be trademarks of their respective owners.<br/>
]]></content></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-12-20T18:02:39.265Z]]></updated><category term="PRESS RELEASE"/><title><![CDATA[John Giannandrea named to Apple’s executive team]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/12/john-giannandrea-named-to-apples-executive-team/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[John Giannandrea named to Apple’s executive team<br/>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced that John Giannandrea has been named to the company’s executive team as senior vice president of Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence Strategy. He joined Apple in April 2018.
<br/>Giannandrea oversees the strategy for AI and Machine Learning across all Apple products and services, as well as the development of Core ML and Siri technologies. His team's focus on advancing and tightly integrating machine learning into Apple products is delivering more personal, intelligent and natural interactions for customers while protecting user privacy. 
<br/>“John hit the ground running at Apple and we are thrilled to have him as part of our executive team,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “Machine learning and AI are important to Apple’s future as they are fundamentally changing the way people interact with technology, and already helping our customers live better lives. We’re fortunate to have John, a leader in the AI industry, driving our efforts in this critical area.” 
<br/>Giannandrea’s team is also helping to enhance the developer experience with tools including Core ML and Create ML, making it easier and faster to integrate machine learning into apps.
<br/>Apple revolutionized personal technology with the introduction of the Macintosh in 1984. Today, Apple leads the world in innovation with iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch and Apple TV. Apple’s four software platforms — iOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS — provide seamless experiences across all Apple devices and empower people with breakthrough services including the App Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay and iCloud. Apple’s more than 100,000 employees are dedicated to making the best products on earth, and to leaving the world better than we found it.<br>

<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Cat Franklin,Apple,cfranklin3@apple.com,(669) 276-1209<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content></entry><entry><updated><![CDATA[2018-12-19T17:59:42.059Z]]></updated><category term="PHOTOS"/><title><![CDATA[Shot on iPhone XR and iPhone XS: Holiday cheer, winter landscapes and more]]></title><id><![CDATA[https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/12/shot-on-iphone-xr-and-iphone-xs-holiday-cheer-winter-landscapes-and-more/]]></id><author><name><![CDATA[Apple Newsroom]]></name></author><content><![CDATA[Shot on iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">R</span> and iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">S</span>: Holiday cheer, winter landscapes and more<br/>Photographers around the world are capturing stunning images this holiday season with iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">r</span>, iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">s</span> and iPhone X<span class="all-small-caps">s</span> Max.
<br/>New camera features including Smart HDR bring better highlight and shadow detail across photos. iPhone’s Portrait mode adds a dramatic background blur, and the larger and deeper pixels improve low-light performance in photos.
<br/>For tips and techniques to help capture great photos and videos on iPhone, visit: <a href="https://www.apple.com/iphone/photography-how-to/" target="_blank">apple.com/iphone/photography-how-to/</a>.
<br/>Press Contacts<br/>Andrew Kelly,Apple,andrewkelly@apple.com,(669) 283-1423<br/>Michele Wyman,Apple,michele_wyman@apple.com,(669) 276-1208<br/>Apple Media Helpline,media.help@apple.com,(408) 974-2042<br/>
]]></content><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/lifestyle/Shot-on-iPhone-holiday-Little-girl-with-string-lights-12192018_big.jpg" rel="enclosure" title="Photo courtesy of Erin Brooks." type="image/jpeg"/></entry></feed>